<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>SimonGanz.com</title>
  <id>http://simonganz.com/</id>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/"/>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-07-01T22:43:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Simon Ganz</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Mac OS X Stuck Registering Updated Components</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/07/mac-os-x-stuck-registering-updated-components/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/07/mac-os-x-stuck-registering-updated-components/</id>
    <published>2013-07-01T22:43:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-01T22:43:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently tried to run software update on my dad's aging Macbook Pro (Snow Leopard, Unibody). Unfortunately, the process stalled during "Registering Updated Components", leaving the computer stuck in the install for 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's how I fixed it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you're sure the install is stuck, hold down the power button to forcibly shut down the computer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restart the computer and open Finder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type ⇧⌘G to bring up the "Go To Folder…" dialogue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type /Library/Updates and hit enter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delete everything in the Updates folder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run Software Update again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, the security update dad's computer was trying to install was somehow corrupted. Redownloading it generated a fresh copy. I hope this is helpful to someone out there with the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Access the iOS 7 Developer Library without a Developer Account</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/06/access-the-ios-developer-library-without-a-developer-account/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/access-the-ios-developer-library-without-a-developer-account/</id>
    <published>2013-06-28T23:34:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-28T23:34:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apple makes &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/" title="Apple Developer Program"&gt;their developer libraries&lt;/a&gt; freely available online with one important exception: Prerelease libraries can only be accessed by registered developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would a non-developer want to read these? Well if you're like me, you might be tech-savvy and curious about iOS 7 or Mavericks but not want to spend $99 to become a registered developer. Luckily there's an easy solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="become-a-safari-developer"&gt;Become a Safari Developer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply sign up to become &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/programs/safari/" title="Safari Developer Program"&gt;a Safari extensions developer&lt;/a&gt;. It's a free program that carries some of the same benefits as a paid iOS or Mac developer membership. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply by providing your address and an Apple ID, you gain the ability to read prerelease developer documents and &lt;a href="http://simonganz.com/2013/06/rounded-rectangles-deprecated/" title="Rounded Rectangles Deprecated"&gt;learn details&lt;/a&gt; about Apple software months before it's released.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rounded Rectangles Deprecated</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/06/rounded-rectangles-deprecated/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/rounded-rectangles-deprecated/</id>
    <published>2013-06-28T23:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-28T23:02:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was reading through the pre-release documentation for iOS 7 and came across this gem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The rounded rectangle button has been deprecated in iOS 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this amusing? Because &lt;a href="http://www.folklore.org/StoryView.py?story=Round_Rects_Are_Everywhere.txt" title="Round Rects Are Everywhere"&gt;rounded rectangles were one of the big user interface innovations of the Macintosh&lt;/a&gt; and were demanded by Steve Jobs himself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Steve suddenly got more intense. "Rectangles with rounded corners are everywhere! Just look around this room!". And sure enough, there were lots of them, like the whiteboard and some of the desks and tables. Then he pointed out the window. "And look outside, there's even more, practically everywhere you look!". He even persuaded Bill to take a quick walk around the block with him, pointing out every rectangle with rounded corners that he could find. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly every button on the Mac and on iOS has been a rounded rectangle for the past thirty years. So there's something charmingly radical about a modern day Apple engineer calmly stating that they've been discontinued.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Add Incredibly Powerful Emacs-style Shortcuts to Mac OS X</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/06/add-emacs-key-bindings-to-mac-os-x/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/add-emacs-key-bindings-to-mac-os-x/</id>
    <published>2013-06-28T22:16:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-28T22:16:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="what-is-emacs"&gt;What is Emacs?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/" title="GNU Emacs"&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; is a very nerdy text editor/email program/development suite/nuclear reactor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's ugly and weird and hard to use because it dates back to a time before computers had mice. But for that same reason, it has amazing tools and shortcuts for rapidly editing and moving through text with only your keyboard. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mac OS X has always had some of &lt;a href="http://www.hcs.harvard.edu/~jrus/Site/System%20Bindings.html" title="Mac OS X Default Key Bindings"&gt;these shortcuts baked in&lt;/a&gt;. For instance, type &lt;em&gt;Ctrl+e&lt;/em&gt; in an OS X text field and the cursor will jump to the end of a line. Type &lt;em&gt;Ctrl+k&lt;/em&gt; and everything between the cursor and the end of the line will be deleted (this is crazy useful when editing; I suggest trying it out).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned these shortcuts for convenience sake a few years back, but recently the trackpad on my Macbook Pro died and I was forced to turn to them full time.&lt;sup id="fnref:magic"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:magic" class="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The problem is that by default, OS X only allows you to use a few select Emacs shortcuts that utilize the ctrl key. Many other powerful Emacs shortcuts are unavailable (including every shortcut that uses the alt key, referred to as the "meta" key in Emacs lingo).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you can change this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="changing-mac-os-x-key-bindings"&gt;Changing Mac OS X Key Bindings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These directions are adapted from &lt;a href="http://www.hcs.harvard.edu/~jrus/site/cocoa-text.html" title="Customizing the Cocoa Text System"&gt;this excellent 2006 article by Jacob Rus&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://brettterpstra.com/2011/08/13/keybinding-madness/" title="Keybinding Madness"&gt;this excellent 2011 post by Brett Terpstra&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a folder named "KeyBindings" in the ~/Library directory.&lt;sup id="fnref:library"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:library" class="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href="https://github.com/ttscoff/KeyBindings/zipball/master" title="Brett Terpstra Killer Keybindings"&gt;this DefaultKeyBinding.dict zip file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unzip the files and place the DefaultKeyBinding.dict file into the newly created KeyBindings folder. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now as soon as you restart any running apps, you'll have access to an &lt;a href="http://ttscoff.github.io/KeyBindings/" title="Brett Terpstra Killer Keybindings"&gt;insanely powerful list of keyboard shortcuts&lt;/a&gt; in almost every Mac OS X application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can do crazy powerful things like uppercase words with &lt;em&gt;Ctrl+U&lt;/em&gt; or copy entire paragraphs instantly by typing &lt;em&gt;Alt+y&lt;/em&gt;. You can move paragraphs using only your keyboard (&lt;em&gt;Ctrl+Command+K&lt;/em&gt;) or delete trailing whitespaces off a line (&lt;em&gt;Ctrl+Alt+Right Arrow&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These key bindings will be overkill for most people, and they may even break a few shortcuts on your computer, but the possibilities are incredible. You can even customize them yourself by editing the DefaultKeyBinding.dict file in a text editor, adding to or tweaking the shortcuts to fit your own workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you spend a lot of time typing text or coding on Mac OS X, you owe it to yourself to play around with a few of these shortcuts and see how they can speed up your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class="footnotes"&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id="fn:magic"&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I eventually bought a &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/magictrackpad/" title="Apple - Magic Trackpad - Multi-Touch trackpad for your desktop."&gt;Magic Trackpad&lt;/a&gt; as a replacement.&lt;a href="#fnref:magic" class="reversefootnote"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id="fn:library"&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;By default, the User's library folder is hidden in Mac OS X. You can access it by opening Finder, selecting the Go menu from the menubar, and holding down the alt key to make the Library option appear.&lt;a href="#fnref:library" class="reversefootnote"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Overturning Prop 8 Affects Future California Initiatives [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.motherjones.com/kevin-drum/2013/06/supreme-court-prop-8-ruling-problem"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/how-overturning-prop-8-affects-future-initiatives/</id>
    <published>2013-06-26T15:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-26T15:03:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One interesting &lt;a href="http://www.motherjones.com/kevin-drum/2013/06/supreme-court-prop-8-ruling-problem" title="Kevin Drum: Supreme Court Prop 8 Ruling Problem"&gt;side note&lt;/a&gt; to today's Supreme Court decision regarding Proposition 8:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Court's reasoning does not take into account the fundamental principles or the practical dynamics of the initiative system in California, which uses this mechanism to control and to bypass public officials—the same officials who would not defend the initiative, an injury the Court now leaves unremedied. The Court's decision also has implications for the 26 other States that use an initiative or popular referendum system and which, like California, may choose to have initiative proponents stand in for the State when public officials decline to defend an initiative in litigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By finding that the proponents of a ballot measure have no standing to sue in federal court, the majority has set up a system in which California and other states can roll back voter initiatives they disagree with by simply refusing to defend them in federal court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is undemocratic and strange, but I have to admit it doesn't bother me much because…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-initiative-system-sucks"&gt;The Initiative System Sucks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initiative process in California is fundamentally broken. Rather than encouraging democracy, it undermines it by diffusing authority for basic decisionmaking in the state. No politician in California is ever responsible for anything because everything is subject to referendum. Voters elect politicians who cannot change how money is spent or raised or how crimes are punished. Then we all complain that nothing gets done in Sacramento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worse, the initiative process distills every complex issue into a binary choice: Yes or no with no potential for compromise or revision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True, sometimes the system does good work. It offers chances for reform on issues like drugs or political redistricting that would probably die in the capitol. But more often it works as a system for millionaires and corporations to foist their personal agendas on California. &lt;a href="http://ballotpedia.org/wiki/index.php/California_Proposition_15,_No_Fees_for_Television_Programs_Transmitted_to_Home_Televisions_(1964)" title="Prop 15 Bans Cable Television"&gt;A 1960s proposition sponsored by theater owners banned cable television in the entire state&lt;/a&gt;, and Proposition 13 famously destroyed local politics in California by capping property taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initiative process has become less odious in recent years (Prop 8 excepted) simply because liberals have gotten better and better at abusing it the way conservatives did thirty years ago. Despite that, I'm glad that the Supreme Court inadvertently smashed up the intiative system in their zeal to avoid deciding on gay marriage directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/06/how-overturning-prop-8-affects-future-initiatives/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Microsoft Caves [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://news.xbox.com/2013/06/update"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/xbox-one-will-play-used-games/</id>
    <published>2013-06-19T23:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-19T23:50:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I previously voiced &lt;a href="http://simonganz.com/2013/05/pa-report-xbox-one-will-kill-used-games/" title="Xbox One Will Kill Used Games"&gt;my displeasure with Microsoft's planned console DRM scheme&lt;/a&gt;. In short, it had more restrictions than digital distribution systems like &lt;a href="http://steampowered.com/" title="Welcome to Steam"&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt; or iOS while offering few of the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn't the only person annoyed. Sony drew blood with &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4vfjdaU3lkA" title="PS4: How to Share Used Games"&gt;vicious and biting videos&lt;/a&gt; at Microsoft's expense, and even &lt;a href="http://www.navytimes.com/article/20130614/OFFDUTY02/306140030" title="Xbox One Has Singlehandedly Alienated the Military"&gt;US military publications spoke out against the system&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft tried to stanch the bleeding, promising that you could share your game with ten friends and log in your console from your phone and etc etc, but these were complicated digital solutions to problems that don't exist with current generation consoles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's not a huge surprise then that Microsoft has folded their hand and &lt;a href="http://news.xbox.com/2013/06/update" title="Xbox One Policy Change Update"&gt;given up on the whole scheme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an unforced error by Microsoft. They designed the new system around their own corporate needs and only belatedly considered how the changes would affect real users. They never made an affirmative case for why this system would be better than the status quo. They just tried to muscle it through. I think the final straw for Microsoft was realizing that none of the major publishers, the very companies this system would most benefit, publicly backed Microsoft's position during the controversy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/06/xbox-one-will-play-used-games/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
