<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>SimonGanz.com</title>
  <id>http://simonganz.com/</id>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/"/>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-12-30T19:03:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Simon Ganz</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Walkscore for Redfin Chrome Extension</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/12/walkscore-for-redfin-chrome-extension/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/12/walkscore-for-redfin-chrome-extension/</id>
    <published>2013-12-30T19:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-12-30T19:03:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;img src="/images/walkscoreExtensionScreenshot-e39932c2.jpg" title="Walkscore Extension for Redfin" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve written &lt;a title="Walkscore for Redfin" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/walkscore-for-redfin-and/jjejooaohjgoapilebkhgigocepijmnp"&gt;a Chrome Extension to show Walkscore results on Redfin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Walkscore" href="http://www.walkscore.com"&gt;Walkscore.com&lt;/a&gt; uses Google Maps to calculate how walkable, bikeable, and transit-friendly a house or apartment is. &lt;a title="Redfin" href="http://www.redfin.com"&gt;Redfin.com&lt;/a&gt; is a real estate site that lists houses and condos for sale. If you’re house hunting, you spend a lot of time bouncing back and forth between these two sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extension also supports &lt;a title="TheMLS" href="http://www.theMLS.com"&gt;TheMLS.com&lt;/a&gt;, a site that real estate agents use to email listings to their clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-to-use-it"&gt;How to Use It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While browsing Redfin.com, clicking on the extension (or using the keyboard shortcut Alt+W on the Mac) pops up a small window displaying the Walkscore.com page for that house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-to-install"&gt;How to Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can install the extension &lt;a title="Walkscore for Redfin" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/walkscore-for-redfin-and/jjejooaohjgoapilebkhgigocepijmnp"&gt;directly from the Chrome Webstore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Kanye West Concert in GIFs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/11/kanye-west-concert-in-gifs/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/11/kanye-west-concert-in-gifs/</id>
    <published>2013-11-26T18:49:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-26T18:49:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;p&gt;On October 19th, 2013, Anna and I attended THE YEEZUS TOUR. The headliner was Kanye West and the opener was Kendrick Lamar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/kanye_gifs/mountain-408748fa.gif" title="Mountain" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a id="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanye wore a freaky gimp mask:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/kanye_gifs/gimp-b82ee581.gif" title="Gimp mask" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Beyonce concert had thousands of swirling lights. Kanye preferred a single spotlight, focused on his favorite subject:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/kanye_gifs/shining_light-f94afea6.gif" title="Spotlight" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanye was an energetic, if not particularly skilled dancer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/kanye_gifs/gimp_dance-ea5e941e.gif" title="Gimp dancing" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all that dancing made Kanye tired, so he took a break on top of these naked ladies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/kanye_gifs/taking_a_break-db72a875.gif" title="Kanye taking a break" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of costume changes, Kanye had mask changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/kanye_gifs/white_mask-1ad4adba.gif" title="White gimp mask" /&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/kanye_gifs/sparkle_face-3804925a.gif" title="Sparkling gimp mask" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually he took the mask off:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/kanye_gifs/maskless-9c9654b8.gif" title="Maskless Kanye" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then his mountain erupted and exploded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/kanye_gifs/eruption-ed32b782.gif" title="Eruption" /&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/kanye_gifs/fire-171dbbf8.gif" title="Fire" /&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/kanye_gifs/explosions-cd543b61.gif" title="Explosions" /&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/kanye_gifs/explosions2-00920a48.gif" title="More explosions" /&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Beyonce Concert in GIFs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/11/beyonce-concert-in-gifs/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/11/beyonce-concert-in-gifs/</id>
    <published>2013-11-16T19:07:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-16T19:07:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;p&gt;On June 28th, 2013, Anna and I attended the BET Experience at LA Live. The headliner was Beyonce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/beyonce_gifs/smoke-176ca351.gif" title="Smoke" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a id="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyonce had elaborate video screens:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/beyonce_gifs/gilded-e4baa69d.gif" title="Screens" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyonce brought a thousand spotlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/beyonce_gifs/searchlights-0809a6e0.gif" title="Searchlights" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyonce flew:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/beyonce_gifs/flying-e5820b61.gif" title="Flying" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyonce blew Anna’s mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/beyonce_gifs/anna-03a08c7a.gif" title="Anna" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Beyonce finished big:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/beyonce_gifs/fin-d2812827.gif" title="Fin" /&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Everpix Shutdown</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/11/everpix-shutdown/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/11/everpix-shutdown/</id>
    <published>2013-11-14T17:45:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-14T17:45:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;p&gt;Sadly, &lt;a title="Everpix Shutdown FAQ" href="https://support.everpix.com/entries/22586374"&gt;Everpix has announced that they are shutting down&lt;/a&gt; and refunding their customers’ money. I’ve added an update to the end of &lt;a title="Everpix Review" href="http://simonganz.com/2013/08/everpix-review/"&gt;my previous review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have become addicted to the easy photo sharing and storage that Everpix offered, and I may take a look to see if Flickr or anyone else have gotten their act together and can act as a reasonable replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ben Affleck Won‘t Ruin Batman vs. Superman</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/ben-affleck-wont-ruin-batman-vs-superman/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/08/ben-affleck-wont-ruin-batman-vs-superman/</id>
    <published>2013-08-25T05:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-25T05:19:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Ben Affleck is the Next Batman" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/08/22/ben-affleck-batman-man-of-steel_n_3801418.html"&gt;Ben Affleck is going to be the next Batman&lt;/a&gt;. And people are angry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if Batman vs. Superman ends up being a terrible movie, it won’t be because of Affleck. It will be because of this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" data-cards="hidden" align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;All this outrage over Affleck, yet no noise of the fact that theyve got less than two years to make a $200M movie they have no script for.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Geoff LaTulippe (@DrGMLaTulippe) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DrGMLaTulippe/statuses/370777905468432384"&gt;August 23, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Batman wearing a Red Sox cap is the least of this movie’s problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Everpix Review</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/everpix-review/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/08/everpix-review/</id>
    <published>2013-08-18T04:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-18T04:55:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;img src="/images/everpix-fe248e04.jpg" title="Everpix" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.everpix.com/"&gt;Everpix&lt;/a&gt; is a subscription photo service that promises unlimited online storage and automatic organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short Review… &lt;strong&gt;It does the first part, storage and sync, perfectly. The second part is still a work in progress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much Longer Review…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-life-and-death-of-iphoto"&gt;The Life and Death of iPhoto&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/everpixIPhoto-f799e180.jpg" title="iPhoto" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to see what a perfect photo collection looks like, just visit an Apple store. On each display computer, you’ll find a copy of iPhoto&lt;sup id="fnref:iPhoto"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:iPhoto" class="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, pre-set with Apple’s idealized vision of a family photo library. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s sample library is organized along every axis. Each image is tagged with Events, Albums, Faces, Keywords, Locations, and even a Five-Star Rating scale. Each sample album is an idyllic vacation or outing, populated exclusively by beautiful, multicultural families who never take bad photos and whose trips happen in confined locations, with no stranger’s faces in the background. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the dream world of iPhoto, as well as its mission statement: &lt;strong&gt;All of your photos, organized&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But throw a real family with real photos at the program and it chokes on every word of that statement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It can’t handle &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; of your photos because there are too many of them and they’re too big. You’re taking 8-megapixel pictures and shooting 1080p video with your iPhone. And god forbid you shoot a &lt;a href="http://photo.net/learn/raw/"&gt;DSLR in RAW format&lt;/a&gt;. Suddenly that 128GB SSD hard-drive in your Macbook Air is full and you’re rationing photos to save space.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And once your photos are in iPhoto, they’re no longer &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt; photos. iPhoto buries them in its own convoluted file system. It only begrudgingly lets you share them using aging plug-ins to services like Facebook and Flickr.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And it’s not &lt;strong&gt;organized&lt;/strong&gt; unless you obsessively do the work of tagging every photo yourself. I like to imagine that the fictional mom in Apple’s sample iPhoto library is suffering from OCD. Are you coming to bed honey? “One minute! Just need to rate all the vacation photos on a 5-point scale!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="everpix-fk-organizing"&gt;Everpix: F**k Organizing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of Everpix is simple: &lt;strong&gt;All of your photos.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everpix gives up on the idea that anyone is going to organize anything. The service is a giant, bottomless bucket into which you quickly and easily dump every photo you take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the service had a motto, it would be &lt;em&gt;“Upload Everything and Let God Sort It Out.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, Everpix &lt;a title="Kill the Algorithm" href="http://blog.everpix.com/post/40309088612/to-reclaim-your-photos-kill-the-algorithm"&gt;claims to organize your photos automatically&lt;/a&gt;, but this is happy talk. A fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re &lt;strong&gt;developing&lt;/strong&gt; image analysis technology that understands your photos and helps you manage your collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re &lt;strong&gt;building&lt;/strong&gt; new ways for you to enjoy and rediscover your pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice the present progressive tense (“-ing”). Automatic organization is something they’re working on, but what’s in the product right now is at best a proof of concept. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everpix hides duplicate photos, tries to guess which photos you’re most interested in, and tries to categorize photos by broad categories like People, Nature, Food, etc. It doesn’t do any of these things particularly well or accurately. &lt;em&gt;But that’s okay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because what Everpix does do is great. &lt;strong&gt;Everpix syncs, stores, and displays decades of photos quickly and effortlessly&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install the Everpix app on your computer and your phone, and soon every photo you’ve ever taken is available everywhere. Despite the complete lack of organization, Everpix’s approach has put me in touch with more old photos in a week than iPhoto did in a decade. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like this hilarious, random New York couple in 2004:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/everpixNewYorkCouple-9748c8ba.jpg" title="The couple that reads together..." /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or my little brother-in-law’s smile in 2007:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/everpixJoey-272398bf.jpg" title="Joey smiles" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t seen either of these photos in years. Probably not since they were taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="alternatives"&gt;Alternatives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flickr&lt;/strong&gt; now offers one terabyte of free storage, but that number is more of a dare than reality. As in “I dare you to somehow manually upload one terabyte of photos when our service caps each upload session to 200 photos.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook&lt;/strong&gt; is designed for sharing. It’s great at that task, but it doesn’t keep high quality copies of your photos and it’s impossible to use the service without sharing everything.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dropbox&lt;/strong&gt; has added some fantastic photo sharing and photo album features. But I have 70 gigs of photos going back a decade. At current prices, that means spending $100-a-year and eventually $200-a-year once I add another 30 gigs of photos.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iCloud Photostream&lt;/strong&gt; is barely a photo service. It’s useful in that it quickly moves photos from one device to all of your devices, but it only stores your last 1000 photos and cannot be upgraded or relied upon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everpix is a solid service. They offer &lt;a href="http://evrpx.co/invite?r=simong%40gmail.com"&gt;18 months&lt;/a&gt; of photo storage for free and unlimited photo storage for $49-a-year. The website and iOS apps are barebones, but each is being &lt;a href="http://status.everpix.com"&gt;rapidly updated&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having all of my photos backed up and instantly accessible is well worth the price of admission. Any other features they add over the next year are gravy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id="update-november-14-2013"&gt;Update: November 14, 2013&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, &lt;a title="Everpix Shutdown FAQ" href="https://support.everpix.com/entries/22586374"&gt;Everpix has announced that they are shutting down&lt;/a&gt; and refunding their customers’ money. The Verge has &lt;a title="Life and Death Inside the World's Best Photo Startup" href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/11/5/5039216/everpix-life-and-death-inside-the-worlds-best-photo-startup"&gt;a longform piece on their final days as a company&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I did not use Everpix every day, I loved the security that came with knowing all of my photos were being synced continuously and effortlessly to the cloud. I also loved being able to dig out a photo from years earlier whenever I wanted using their web and iOS applications. As of now, I have no idea how I’ll replace the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class="footnotes"&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id="fn:iPhoto"&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;iPhoto 2011 to be exact. Apple hasn’t updated it in years and it doesn’t sync with its newer iOS counterparts at all. &lt;a href="#fnref:iPhoto" class="reversefootnote"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
