<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>SimonGanz.com</title>
  <id>http://simonganz.com/</id>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/"/>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-06-07T16:32:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Simon Ganz</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Will PRISM Harm the US Tech Industry [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/moneybox/2013/06/07/prism_tech_exports_will_nsa_revelations_block_american_companies_abroad.html"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/prism-harms-us-tech-industry/</id>
    <published>2013-06-07T16:32:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-07T16:32:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Imagine if it had come out in the 1980s that Japanese intelligence agencies were tracking the location of every Toyota and Honda vehicle, and then the big response from the Japanese government was to reassure people that &lt;em&gt;Japanese&lt;/em&gt; citizens weren't being spied upon this way. There would have been—legitimately—massive political pressure to get Japanese cars out of foreign markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Yglesias has &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/moneybox/2013/06/07/prism_tech_exports_will_nsa_revelations_block_american_companies_abroad.html" title="Prism Tech Exports: Will NSA Revelations Block American Companies Abroad"&gt;a great blog post&lt;/a&gt; puncturing some of the insular, parochial American reactions to &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/us-intelligence-mining-data-from-nine-us-internet-companies-in-broad-secret-program/2013/06/06/3a0c0da8-cebf-11e2-8845-d970ccb04497_story.html" title="US Intelligence Mining Data from Nine US Internet Companies"&gt;the spying scandal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very few Americans seem to care about civil liberties or the Bill of Rights, but have we considered how these national security programs could hobble our biggest exports? If you lived in another country and were using products made by US companies like Google, Apple, Facebook, etc., would you be okay with those products feeding your information directly to a foreign government?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/06/prism-harms-us-tech-industry/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Microsoft Clarifies Xbox One Used Games Policy [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://kotaku.com/the-xbox-one-just-had-a-very-bad-day-511766497"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/xbox-one-used-games/</id>
    <published>2013-06-07T04:53:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-07T04:53:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kotaku has &lt;a href="http://kotaku.com/the-xbox-one-just-had-a-very-bad-day-511766497"&gt;a cynical rundown&lt;/a&gt; of how Xbox One will handle used games. Basically, &lt;a href="http://simonganz.com/2013/05/pa-report-xbox-one-will-kill-used-games/"&gt;my fears&lt;/a&gt; are confirmed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Xbox One will allow the sale of used games, at "participating retailers", but only if the publisher allows it. Publishers being the very people opposed most fiercely to used video game sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft understands that this change is going to piss off a lot of people, so they're trying to pull a Pontius Pilate and offload the final decision onto the publishers. "Oh we really wish you could still buy and sell used games, but we left it as an option for the publishers, and those gosh darn meanies didn't implement it!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/06/xbox-one-used-games/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Get Rid of Fruit Flies</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/06/get-rid-of-fruit-flies/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/get-rid-of-fruit-flies/</id>
    <published>2013-06-07T04:24:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-07T04:24:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fruit flies are tiny insects that lay their eggs on the skin of ripe or fermenting fruit. They're harmless, but you'll occasionally find a batch of them swirling around your kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's an easy way to get rid of them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a wine glass.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour in some apple cider vinegar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put in a couple drops of dishwashing liquid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flies are attracted to the vinegar, but the curved glass and the dishwashing soap make it impossible for them to land on the surface, so they fall through and drown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other &lt;a href="http://insects.about.com/od/insectssociety/qt/Make-A-Vinegar-Trap-For-Fruit-Flies.htm"&gt;elaborate traps&lt;/a&gt; you can make (and obviously you should clean your kitchen as well), but the simple trap works very well. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Wall Street Journal: Death by Bicycle [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://on.wsj.com/19tHx3t"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/wall-street-journal-death-by-bicycle/</id>
    <published>2013-06-03T15:22:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-03T15:22:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do not ask me to enter the minds of the totalitarians running this city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wall Street Journal has done the world a great service by posting &lt;a href="http://on.wsj.com/19tHx3t" title="WSJ: Death By Bicycle"&gt;a video interview with one of their editorial board members&lt;/a&gt;. In five excruciating minutes, Dorothy Rabinowitz demonstrates that the Journal's editorials are written by elderly cranks who think New York's bike-share program is akin to Stalin's Five Year Plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I love about this interview is that you could have a more articulate discussion about bike-sharing with any random person on the street. Despite being an editorial board member for a prestigious national paper, she brings no factual knowledge or experience to bear. She makes repeated ad hominem attacks, and she relies entirely on anecdotal evidence gathered from her isolated life as a very wealthy woman living in New York. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is your crazy Aunt or Uncle being given the ear of 2.4 million subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/06/wall-street-journal-death-by-bicycle/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Star Trek's Radical Cast [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://obsidianwings.blogs.com/obsidian_wings/2013/05/star-trek-could-use-a-hard-reboot.html"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/star-trek-cast/</id>
    <published>2013-06-02T18:04:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-02T18:04:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src="/images/StarTrekTOSCrew-ca539f5d.jpg" title="Star Trek Original Crew" /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At the time, though, this was disconcertingly radical, it didn't respect conventional norms. There was a black woman who wasn't a cook or maid; there was a Russian (the Enemy of the current Cold War), and a Japanese (an Enemy from a previous war). Sulu and Chekov looked like the Bad Guys – but they weren't. Spock, too, looked weird, alien, almost devilish – as though he, too, was supposed to be a Bad Guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here, the author veers into goofy fanfiction, recasting and gender swapping the parts in JJ Abrams' Star Trek in ways that would be as radical to modern audiences as the Original Series cast was to 1960s audiences. In the fantasy cast, there are no white males, and supreme effort is taken to have ethnically appropriate actors for every role (rather than fudging English for Scottish, this Asian for that Asian, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author's approach is too nerdy even for me and gives zero deference to the financial realities of Hollywood filmmaking. But there's an interesting point here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Star Trek is about the future. But more specifically, Star Trek is about a radically utopian and progressive future that goes much deeper than transporters and warp drives. Recreating the relationships and stories from the original cast is fun and makes for entertaining films. But it also turns the franchise into something harmless. It makes the whole thing retro rather than radical. And something important is lost in the process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/06/star-trek-cast/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Rick Perry Vetoes Buy American Bill [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.opposingviews.com/i/news/rick-perry-vetoes-buy-american-bill-approved-145-0-texas-house"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/05/rick-perry-vetoes-buy-american-bill/</id>
    <published>2013-05-30T16:43:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-05-30T16:43:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"Gov. Perry by his veto has undercut the creation and preservation of manufacturing jobs in Texas and the U.S." Texas AFL-CIO President Becky Moeller said. "These jobs are critical to our economic success.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed some &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/1fc3g7/rick_perry_vetoes_buy_american_bill_approved_1450/"&gt;sturm und drang online&lt;/a&gt; about Texas Governor Rick Perry vetoing a bipartisan "Buy American" bill.&lt;sup id="fnref:buy"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:buy" class="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Interestingly, people angered by the bill include both liberal labor unions and nationalist conservatives. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think "Buy American" bills encourage shoddy governance. Supporting US manufacturing is a noble goal, but it shouldn't take hostage all other government responsibilities. If the federal government or a state or a city &lt;a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2012/may/24/local/la-me-0524-rail-cars-20120524"&gt;wants to build a train system&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, they should focus on hiring vendors who will do the best possible job building a train system. Many of those vendors will be American and will generate jobs in the US, but the point of building the train should be to improve transportation, not to create those jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding rules like "Buy American" encourages every government project to focus on local cronyism, rather than building whatever the hell they're supposed to build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class="footnotes"&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id="fn:buy"&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Texas already has a "Buy American" law. This bill just added more types of goods.&lt;a href="#fnref:buy" class="reversefootnote"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/05/rick-perry-vetoes-buy-american-bill/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
