<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>SimonGanz.com</title>
  <id>http://simonganz.com/</id>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/"/>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-06-12T20:08:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Simon Ganz</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Story vs. Plot [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://badassdigest.com/2013/06/12/film-crit-hulk-smash-the-age-of-the-convoluted-blockbuster/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/story-vs-plot/</id>
    <published>2013-06-12T20:08:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-12T20:08:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://badassdigest.com/2013/06/12/film-crit-hulk-smash-the-age-of-the-convoluted-blockbuster/" title="The Age of the Convoluted Blockbuster"&gt;Film Crit Hulk's latest article&lt;/a&gt; dives into convoluted blockbusters like &lt;em&gt;Star Trek Into Darkness&lt;/em&gt;, and he makes a particularly deep point about the difference between story and plot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And so when we look at the stories in Abrams’ work we don’t find much in the way of story at all. We find plots. It’s all master secretive plans built on reveals upon reveals upon reveals. We watch as brilliant characters play a high-stakes game of trying to outsmart each other. We watch those plans get teased out in incomprehensible ways. We watch them unravel a story without a hint of organic discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lost&lt;/em&gt; fans should be shaking their heads in recognition right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hulk's post clarifies a lesson I've been trying to learn. &lt;strong&gt;Screenplay is a way to tell a story, but it is not the story itself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Story is something underneath the screenplay. It's what the dialogue, action, plot, and pacing of the screenplay are trying to convey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a story, a screenplay is just empty mechanics. It's hollow and unfilling. In short, it's &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1446714/" title="Prometheus (2012)"&gt;Prometheus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/06/story-vs-plot/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ iCloud Keychain [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.apple.com/osx/preview/#icloud-keychain"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/icloud-keychain/</id>
    <published>2013-06-10T23:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-10T23:03:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src="/images/icloudKeychainPassword-07d4eeb4.jpg" title="iCloud Keychain" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am so glad to hear that &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/osx/preview/#icloud-keychain" title="iCloud Keychain"&gt;Apple is adding a password auto-generator&lt;/a&gt; to future versions of Safari on Mac and iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who has worked tech support as a personal assistant (and for my parents), I can tell you that people use terrible passwords. They pick a common word, maybe slap a number on the end, and then use that same password for everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normal people don't realize &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/security/2013/05/how-crackers-make-minced-meat-out-of-your-passwords/" title="How Crackers Make Minced Meat out of Your Passwords"&gt;how easy it is to crack even the most eXtR3m3!! passwords&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href="http://agilebits.com/onepassword" title="1Password - AgileBits"&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; to generate random unique passwords for every online account, and I've tried to set that system up for other people too. But it's fiddly and complicated. It requires a browser extension, and it requires the user to remember to actually use the damn thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple's solution will not be the best password solution, but just as they did with personal backups and Time Machine, they're taking something complicated and vital and distilling it down to something simple enough for my mom to use. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this will be a huge security improvement for average users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/06/icloud-keychain/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Why Google Killed Reader [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2013/06/why-google-reader-got-the-ax/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/why-google-killed-reader/</id>
    <published>2013-06-08T05:23:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-08T05:23:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"As a culture we have moved into a realm where the consumption of news is a near-constant process. Users with smartphones and tablets are consuming news in bits and bites throughout the course of the day — replacing the old standard behaviors of news consumption over breakfast along with a leisurely read at the end of the day."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't like &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2013/06/why-google-reader-got-the-ax/" title="Why Google Reader Got the Axe"&gt;Google's explanation for killing Google Reader&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, Twitter and social media have changed how we consume news and internet posts. But the niche Google Reader and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS" title="RSS - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; serve is not about "leisurely" browsing of the internet over eggs and bacon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By checking my RSS feed, I can skim and select from hundreds of stories from my favorite sites and authors in less than a minute.&lt;sup id="fnref:small"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:small" class="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, Twitter and Facebook give me a random shotgun blast full of memes, links, and advertisements. I do not want to like or follow every public figure, author, or company that interests me and then have those people shit up my social feed. My social feed is just that, social. It shows me what &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; people think I should be reading, which is not always what &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; want to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand that RSS has always been a niche technology and that Google is probably making the right choice by focusing their efforts on more casual users. But I think Wired hits on a darker, potentially more accurate explanation for the change:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now and Plus do one thing: They keep you in Google’s world. It’s a de-emphasis of content source. In other words, rather than reading Cat Fancy religiously, you’re reading the Animals category religiously — a category populated by the sites Google’s products think you’ll enjoy most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class="footnotes"&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id="fn:small"&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I can also subscribe to small sites and webcomics without worrying that I'll miss their rare updates in my stream.&lt;a href="#fnref:small" class="reversefootnote"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/06/why-google-killed-reader/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Will PRISM Harm the US Tech Industry [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/moneybox/2013/06/07/prism_tech_exports_will_nsa_revelations_block_american_companies_abroad.html"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/prism-harms-us-tech-industry/</id>
    <published>2013-06-07T16:32:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-07T16:32:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Imagine if it had come out in the 1980s that Japanese intelligence agencies were tracking the location of every Toyota and Honda vehicle, and then the big response from the Japanese government was to reassure people that &lt;em&gt;Japanese&lt;/em&gt; citizens weren't being spied upon this way. There would have been—legitimately—massive political pressure to get Japanese cars out of foreign markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Yglesias has &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/moneybox/2013/06/07/prism_tech_exports_will_nsa_revelations_block_american_companies_abroad.html" title="Prism Tech Exports: Will NSA Revelations Block American Companies Abroad"&gt;a great blog post&lt;/a&gt; puncturing some of the insular, parochial American reactions to &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/us-intelligence-mining-data-from-nine-us-internet-companies-in-broad-secret-program/2013/06/06/3a0c0da8-cebf-11e2-8845-d970ccb04497_story.html" title="US Intelligence Mining Data from Nine US Internet Companies"&gt;the spying scandal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very few Americans seem to care about civil liberties or the Bill of Rights, but have we considered how these national security programs could hobble our biggest exports? If you lived in another country and were using products made by US companies like Google, Apple, Facebook, etc., would you be okay with those products feeding your information directly to a foreign government?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/06/prism-harms-us-tech-industry/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Microsoft Clarifies Xbox One Used Games Policy [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://kotaku.com/the-xbox-one-just-had-a-very-bad-day-511766497"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/xbox-one-used-games/</id>
    <published>2013-06-07T04:53:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-07T04:53:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kotaku has &lt;a href="http://kotaku.com/the-xbox-one-just-had-a-very-bad-day-511766497"&gt;a cynical rundown&lt;/a&gt; of how Xbox One will handle used games. Basically, &lt;a href="http://simonganz.com/2013/05/pa-report-xbox-one-will-kill-used-games/"&gt;my fears&lt;/a&gt; are confirmed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Xbox One will allow the sale of used games, at "participating retailers", but only if the publisher allows it. Publishers being the very people opposed most fiercely to used video game sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft understands that this change is going to piss off a lot of people, so they're trying to pull a Pontius Pilate and offload the final decision onto the publishers. "Oh we really wish you could still buy and sell used games, but we left it as an option for the publishers, and those gosh darn meanies didn't implement it!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/06/xbox-one-used-games/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Get Rid of Fruit Flies</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/06/get-rid-of-fruit-flies/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/06/get-rid-of-fruit-flies/</id>
    <published>2013-06-07T04:24:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-07T04:24:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fruit flies are tiny insects that lay their eggs on the skin of ripe or fermenting fruit. They're harmless, but you'll occasionally find a batch of them swirling around your kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's an easy way to get rid of them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a wine glass.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour in some apple cider vinegar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put in a couple drops of dishwashing liquid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flies are attracted to the vinegar, but the curved glass and the dishwashing soap make it impossible for them to land on the surface, so they fall through and drown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other &lt;a href="http://insects.about.com/od/insectssociety/qt/Make-A-Vinegar-Trap-For-Fruit-Flies.htm"&gt;elaborate traps&lt;/a&gt; you can make (and obviously you should clean your kitchen as well), but the simple trap works very well. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
