<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>SimonGanz.com</title>
  <id>http://simonganz.com/</id>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/"/>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-11-29T11:35:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Simon Ganz</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Ranndy Random Name Generator Updated</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/11/ranndy-random-name-generator-updated/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2014/11/ranndy-random-name-generator-updated/</id>
    <published>2014-11-29T11:35:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-11-29T11:35:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;p&gt;I’ve released a new version of &lt;a title="Ranndy Random Name Generator" href="http://ranndy.com"&gt;Ranndy.com&lt;/a&gt;, my random name generator for use in fiction writing and baby naming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-starts-with-feature"&gt;New Starts With Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy can now show you names that start with certain letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you enter “Jo” in the Starts With field, Ranndy will only show you names that start with “Jo” like John, Jordan, Jose, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ranndy/starts-with-65d795cc.png" title="Ranndy Starts With Feature" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-exclusion-feature"&gt;New Exclusion Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy can also do the opposite of Starts With, showing you names that DON’T start with certain letters. Just use the * character in the Starts With field. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you enter “D*, S*, P*” in the Starts With field, Ranndy won’t show you any names that start with D, S, or P. This is useful when you’re writing a screenplay and don’t want too many characters whose names sound or look similar on the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ranndy/exclusion-74a89306.png" title="Ranndy Exclusion Feature" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-force-name-feature"&gt;New Force Name Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy now lets you force a first or last name. If you already know a first or last name that you love, you can force that name with the ^ character in the Starts With field. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you enter “Smith^” in the Last Name Starts With field, then Ranndy will show you random first names but every last name will be “Smith”. This is useful for baby naming and also creating family members for characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ranndy/force-name-f090b540.png" title="Ranndy Force Name Feature" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2 id="popularity-tweaks"&gt;Popularity Tweaks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also made some tweaks to how Ranndy ranks first names by popularity. The default setting of “High” popularity is now much broader, which should give a better variety of names without including too many weird names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="project-page"&gt;Project Page&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Ranndy, you can visit &lt;a title="Ranndy Random Name Generator" href="http://simonganz.com/2014/06/ranndy-random-name-generator/"&gt;my first blog post about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Making a Digital Will for Your Online Accounts</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/09/making-a-digital-will-for-your-online-accounts/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2014/09/making-a-digital-will-for-your-online-accounts/</id>
    <published>2014-09-21T16:23:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2014-09-21T16:23:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;h2 id="the-problem-death"&gt;The Problem: Death&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/death-d17bddd2.jpg" title="Death" /&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align:right; margin-bottom: -20px;"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/pedrosz/5578743262/in/photolist-dqGruE-5SuHtq-6dbaBf-8DDXGt-bsKmci-9aRZK2-7U24t8-4CwBoY-4wskbr-9uYw1E-m9jryL-7Z5xz2-9cb36s-9cAs7C-9LDkcC-dqGrFL-dYN8NR-9i2q1m-nsNaSW-c2Z8S9-dqGhvn-ot7cxc-9jRzE5-ahoi86-2yKq35-eg9fuW-9kuX6N-9atqQ-8h7tpM-mUepW-cYWWj3-4JvWT4-57WvKT-bndFjR-cLh3pw-7cvtQ2-aVFXc-ePGGNz-9d51VP-dqGrxb-9dnysQ-5i9jvH-58jZXm-a2uYFY-ft1G9Z-6UfB3T-3Tu6bj-8dwz8q-4y9XXp-9G8Z8c/"&gt;© Pedro Szekely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m the designated nerd in my family, so I handle all of our online accounts. To keep them secure, I use randomly generated, unique passwords and two-factor authentication. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that means that my wife doesn’t know the online logins for our iTunes account, our bank and retirement accounts, our gas company, our cable company, our water and power company, and so on and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if I died or was suddenly incapacitated? How would she access our accounts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need a system that’s secure. I don’t want to weaken all my online accounts just for the off chance that I get hit by a bus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need a system that can outlive my hardware. What if my hypothetical death also destroyed my laptop, tablet, and phone?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need a system that can be easily understood by my tech illiterate survivors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-solution"&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="ingredient-list"&gt;Ingredient List&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="1Password - AgileBits" href="https://agilebits.com/onepassword"&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="Dropbox" href="https://www.dropbox.com/"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Printed or handwritten letter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secure physical location (safe, deposit box, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="step-one-put-all-your-passwords-in-1password"&gt;Step One: Put all your passwords in 1Password&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="1Password - AgileBits" href="https://agilebits.com/onepassword"&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; is a password management app available for Mac, Windows, and iOS. It saves your passwords in a secure vault with a master password. Instead of having to remember hundreds of weak passwords, you only have to remember one strong password. The app can generate random, unique passwords for all your online accounts, so if a service gets hacked, your other accounts are safe because each has a unique and unguessable password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="step-two-put-your-1password-vault-in-dropbox"&gt;Step Two: Put your 1Password vault in Dropbox&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1Password can &lt;a title="How To: Configure Dropbox Syncing" href="https://help.agilebits.com/1Password3/configure_dropbox_on_mac.html"&gt;store your secure password vault in your Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; account. That means that by leaving detailed instructions and a few key passwords, all of your online account information can be accessed from one simple file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="step-three-write-a-letter-explaining-how-to-access-your-dropbox-account-and-1password-vault"&gt;Step Three: Write a letter explaining how to access your Dropbox account and 1Password vault&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The letter should be stored in a secure location like a safe or safety deposit box in a sealed envelope with the date written on it. And you should tell people important to you about the letter and where to find it. If you have a legal will for your estate, you should mention the letter in that will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing the letter is the hardest step. It should include the following information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your email account username and password. If your family needs to reset any of your passwords, they’ll need access to your email.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Dropbox username and password.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your 1Password Master Password.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your passcode for your cellphone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Detailed instructions for how to access the 1Password master vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id="example-text"&gt;Example Text&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some example text from my own letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accessing a two-factor authentication protected gmail account:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My Gmail account is protected with two-factor authentication. This means you need both my password and the Google Authenticator app on my iPhone in order to access it. If you can’t access my phone, you can use a special one-time only backup code to get into my Gmail account without using the authenticator. Once you log in with a backup code, you should turn off two-factor authentication so that you don’t get locked out of the account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accessing Dropbox and 1Password:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My writing as well as an encrypted archive containing all of my online passwords can be found in my Dropbox account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Inside my Dropbox is a file called 1Password.agilekeychain. 
This is an encrypted archive that contains all of my passwords, including those for important accounts like my bank account. It can be opened using a program called 1Password which is available at https://agilebits.com/onepassword. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id="bonus-list-your-online-assets"&gt;Bonus: List Your Online Assets&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passing on all of your online accounts to your survivors isn’t useful if they don’t know what’s worth saving. At the end of the letter, write down a list of every online asset that’s important or valuable to you. For instance, web domains, online photo storage accounts, and anything you’ve written online and want preserved.&lt;/p&gt;

</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fountain Loader for Google Drive</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/06/fountain-loader-for-google-drive/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2014/06/fountain-loader-for-google-drive/</id>
    <published>2014-06-27T20:48:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-27T20:48:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Fountain Loader" href="http://fountainloader.com"&gt;Fountain Loader&lt;/a&gt; is an online previewer for &lt;a title="Fountain: A markup language for screenwriting&amp;quot;" href="http://fountain.io/"&gt;Fountain screenplay documents&lt;/a&gt;. It works with Google Drive™, making it easier to write screenplays in Google Docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="video-container"&gt;
    &lt;video autoplay loop controls poster="http://fountainloader.com/videos/fountain-loader-poster.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;source id="webmsource" src="http://fountainloader.com/videos/fountain-loader.webm" type="video/webm"&gt;
    &lt;source id="mp4source" src="http://fountainloader.com/videos/fountain-loader.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;
    &lt;img src="http://fountainloader.com/videos/fountain-loader.gif"&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="why-did-i-make-this"&gt;Why did I make this&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Docs is the best collaborative writing program I’ve found. It lets me and my writing partner work on a script simultaneously, sometimes even working on the same sentence at the same time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Google Docs is butt ugly. It doesn’t even have a decent Courier font.&lt;sup id="fnref:font"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:font" class="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I’m used to writing code and staring at ugly markup, but my writing partner can’t stand it. Google Docs just doesn’t look like a screenplay to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fountain Loader bridges the visual gap between Google Docs and the final script. It loads our script as we work on it and generates a preview in another tab. It can also watch the file and update as the document changes.&lt;sup id="fnref:caveat"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:caveat" class="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="features"&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pretty damn accurate:&lt;/strong&gt; The preview should be very close to how your script will look when output by &lt;a title="Highland - Quote-Unquote Apps" href="http://quoteunquoteapps.com/highland/"&gt;John August’s Highland app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsive:&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple layouts so you can preview screenplays on your phone or tablet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detect Changes mode:&lt;/strong&gt; Watches your document and generates new previews with each change.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safe:&lt;/strong&gt; Fountain Loader renders everything locally in Javascript. Your screenplay goes directly from Google Drive to your browser without being saved on a server somewhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="possible-future-features"&gt;Possible Future Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Fountain outlining elements to create fast-links to jump through a script (e.g. jump to act two).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toggle to hide notes and outline elements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="link"&gt;Link&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out at &lt;a href="http://fountainloader.com"&gt;http://fountainloader.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class="footnotes"&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id="fn:font"&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a title="Google Fonts Cousine" href="https://www.google.com/fonts/specimen/Cousine"&gt;cousine&lt;/a&gt;, a coding font that has the same metrics as Courier. &lt;a href="#fnref:font" class="reversefootnote"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id="fn:caveat"&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Caveat: This feature depends on &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/drive/web/manage-changes"&gt;Google Drive’s change feed system&lt;/a&gt;, which doesn’t update as fast as you might guess. It groups changes together and only updates every few minutes. &lt;a href="#fnref:caveat" class="reversefootnote"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ranndy Random Name Generator</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/06/ranndy-random-name-generator/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2014/06/ranndy-random-name-generator/</id>
    <published>2014-06-20T22:18:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-20T22:18:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ranndyInterface-283c7de4.png" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Ranndy Random Name Generator" href="http://ranndy.com"&gt;Ranndy.com&lt;/a&gt; is a random name generator for use in fiction writing and baby naming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site is mobile friendly and presents an infinite scroll of random names with hundreds of millions of possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="year-race-and-popularity"&gt;Year, Race, and Popularity…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy uses US Census data, so you can get very specific about what sort of random name you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’re writing a character who should be roughly 30 years old, you can ask Ranndy to only show you popular names from 1984.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’re writing a character with a specific racial/ethnic background (Native American sheriff, African American businessman, etc.) you can ask Ranndy to only show you surnames associated with that racial/ethnic group.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a truly out there name, you can ask Ranndy to only show you unpopular names. For instance, only five unlucky babies in the US were named Ranndy with two n’s in the year 2005.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="names-that-start-with"&gt;Names That Start With…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy can show you names that start with certain letters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you enter “Jo” in the Starts With field, Ranndy will only show you names that start with “Jo” like John, Jordan, Jose, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="excluding-names"&gt;Excluding Names…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy can also do the opposite, showing you names that DON’T start with certain letters. Just use the * character. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you enter “D*, S*, P*” in the Starts With field, Ranndy won’t show you any names that start with D, S, or P. This is useful when you’re writing a screenplay and don’t want too many characters whose names sound or look similar on the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="forcing-a-name"&gt;Forcing a Name…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy also doesn’t have to be quite so random. If you already know a first or last name that you love, you can force that name with the ^ character. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you enter “Smith^” in the Last Name Starts With field, then Ranndy will show you random first names but every last name will be “Smith”. This is useful for baby naming and also creating family members for characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="change-log"&gt;Change Log&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;v0.3.0 - 11/29/2014&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added “Starts With” features.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reworked first name popularity system. Now there are only high and low popularity choices instead of high, medium, and low. This should give a better variety of names in default searches without including too many weird names.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changed how Ranndy reacts when a request brings up very few results. Example: If your parameters only brought up 10 possible last names, Ranndy will now repeat those 10 names over and over with randomly generated first names, rather than only showing you 10 total results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="technical-details"&gt;Technical Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy’s front end is &lt;a href="http://backbonejs.org/"&gt;backbone.js&lt;/a&gt; and its backend is &lt;a href="http://expressjs.com/"&gt;node.js/express&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Friday Night Lights Reunion</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/02/friday-night-lights-parenthood-webisodes/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2014/02/friday-night-lights-parenthood-webisodes/</id>
    <published>2014-02-13T19:44:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-13T19:44:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;p&gt;Partway through last year, I got an amazing opportunity to work on a secret project for NBC. Today that project is out. It’s a crossover between the cast of &lt;em&gt;Friday Night Lights&lt;/em&gt; (one of the best dramas of the last ten years) with NBC’s &lt;em&gt;Parenthood&lt;/em&gt; (one of the best dramas on TV today).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a fan of FNL, I think you’ll really dig this little reunion. It’s called Friday Night at the Luncheonette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="video-container"&gt;
	&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/0UbUZjfvq1c?list=PLRUSbbQynOdH2NI5xLJ03K_tdIaTRTukk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote episode three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Friday Night at the Luncheonette" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0UbUZjfvq1c&amp;amp;list=PLRUSbbQynOdH2NI5xLJ03K_tdIaTRTukk&amp;amp;feature=share"&gt;[Youtube]&lt;/a&gt; – [&lt;a title="Friday Night at the Luncheonette" href="http://www.nbc.com/parenthood/video/friday-night-at-the-luncheonette/2745592"&gt;NBC Video&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Walk Score for Redfin Chrome Extension</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/12/walkscore-for-redfin-chrome-extension/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/12/walkscore-for-redfin-chrome-extension/</id>
    <published>2013-12-30T11:03:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2013-12-30T11:03:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;img src="/images/walkscoreExtensionScreenshot-e39932c2.jpg" title="Walkscore Extension for Redfin" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve written &lt;a title="Walkscore for Redfin" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/walkscore-for-redfin-and/jjejooaohjgoapilebkhgigocepijmnp"&gt;a Chrome Extension to show Walk Score rankings on Redfin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Walkscore" href="http://www.walkscore.com"&gt;Walk Score&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses Google Maps to calculate how walkable, bikeable, and transit-friendly a house or apartment is. &lt;a title="Redfin" href="http://www.redfin.com"&gt;Redfin.com&lt;/a&gt; is a real estate site that lists houses and condos for sale. I’m house hunting, so I’ve spent a lot of time bouncing back and forth between these two sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-to-use-it"&gt;How to Use It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While browsing Redfin, clicking on the extension (or using the keyboard shortcut Alt+W on the Mac) pops up a small window displaying the Walkscore.com page for that house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extension also supports &lt;a title="TheMLS" href="http://www.theMLS.com"&gt;TheMLS.com&lt;/a&gt;, a site that real estate agents use to email listings to their clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-to-install"&gt;How to Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can install the extension &lt;a title="Walkscore for Redfin" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/walkscore-for-redfin-and/jjejooaohjgoapilebkhgigocepijmnp"&gt;directly from the Chrome Webstore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
