<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>SimonGanz.com</title>
  <id>http://simonganz.com/</id>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/"/>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-10-17T14:13:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Simon Ganz</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Hunt the Truth Season Two</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2015/10/hunt-the-truth-season-two/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2015/10/hunt-the-truth-season-two/</id>
    <published>2015-10-17T14:13:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2015-10-17T14:13:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;img src="/images/HTT2-178d68af.jpg" title="Hunt the Truth ODST" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://huntthetruth.tumblr.com/" title="HUNT the TRUTH"&gt;Hunt the Truth season two&lt;/a&gt; is out and I wrote several episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hunt the Truth is an award winning radio drama/podcast set in the Halo universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Season one was structured like &lt;a href="http://serialpodcast.org" title="Serial Podcast"&gt;Serial&lt;/a&gt;, the This American Life spinoff podcast that investigated a single murder over a season of podcast episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Season two is structured like an old fashioned radio drama. So it’s a format invented in the early 1900s telling stories in a videogame universe set in the 26th century. Which is pretty awesome if you think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="season-two"&gt;Season Two&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to listen, Aaron and I wrote episodes three through six for season two. They’re available on the &lt;a href="http://huntthetruth.tumblr.com/" title="HUNT the TRUTH"&gt;Hunt The Truth tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/huntthetruth" title="HUNT the TRUTH - Free Listening on SoundCloud"&gt;SoundCloud pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing our episodes was unbelievably fun for a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Amazing freedom. In television and web video, Aaron and I are always limited by budget. No one’s going to give us a hundred million dollars to film a spaceship battle no matter how awesome and funny we promise it’s going to be. But in radio, there is no budget! The only limits are the sound design and the audience’s patience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s friggin Halo. I still remember rushing home from high school and tearing open my brand new Xbox. I’d been waiting for months for the console and years for Halo, so when the awesomely over the top &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bat1QaCtDhY" title="Halo Menu Music"&gt;Halo menu music&lt;/a&gt; started (monks chanting and harmonizing, 480p graphics sizzling my eyeballs), it felt like a borderline spiritual moment. Now, all these years later, it’s just so exciting to know that I got to write in a little corner of that universe.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Infinite thanks to the &lt;a href="http://www.ayzenberg.com/" title="Ayzenberg Group"&gt;Ayzenberg creative agency&lt;/a&gt; for inviting us to work on this with them and their awesome in-house writers.&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>About a Babymoon</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2015/08/about-a-babymoon/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2015/08/about-a-babymoon/</id>
    <published>2015-08-25T21:18:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-25T21:18:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;img src="/images/about-a-boy-de83aa38.jpg" title="About a Boy" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though NBC cancelled About a Boy earlier this year, thankfully the episode my partner and I wrote was still made and produced. Episode 217, About a Babymoon, is now available online at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/About-a-Babymoon/dp/B011CGNKQQ/ref=as_sl_pc_qf_sp_asin_til?tag=simongcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=AX2W3CAHYG63LZZW&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B011CGNKQQ"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/tv-season/about-a-babymoon/id916041060?i=1020546458"&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fountain Loader 2.0</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2015/06/fountain-loader-2-0/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2015/06/fountain-loader-2-0/</id>
    <published>2015-06-29T07:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-29T07:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’m releasing a major new update to my screenwriting app, &lt;a href="http://fountainloader.com" title="Fountain Loader for Google Docs"&gt;Fountain Loader&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="video-container"&gt;
    &lt;video autoplay loop controls poster="http://fountainloader.com/videos/fountain-loader-2.png"&gt;
    &lt;source id="webmsource" src="http://fountainloader.com/videos/fountain-loader-2.webm" type="video/webm"&gt;
    &lt;source id="mp4source" src="http://fountainloader.com/videos/fountain-loader-2.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;
    &lt;img src="http://fountainloader.com/videos/fountain-loader-2.gif"&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quickly recap, Fountain Loader is a web app that makes it easy to write screenplays in Google Docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It builds off the brilliant work of &lt;a href="http://johnaugust.com/" title="John August"&gt;John August&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://nimayousefi.com/" title="Nima Yousefi"&gt;Nima Yousefi&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://prolost.com/" title="Prolost"&gt;Stu Maschwitz&lt;/a&gt; who created the &lt;a href="http://fountain.io/" title="Fountain - A markup language for screenwriting."&gt;fountain screenwriting format&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the hell is a screenwriting format? Well fountain is really just a basic set of formatting rules. If you write text that follows those rules, then that text can be easily converted into a finished screenplay using great programs like &lt;a href="http://quoteunquoteapps.com/highland/" title="Highland - Quote-Unquote Apps"&gt;Highland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://slugline.co/" title="Slugline. Simply Screenwriting."&gt;Slugline&lt;/a&gt;, and now Fountain Loader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a &lt;a href="http://fountain.io/_downloads/Big%20Fish.fountain" title="Big Fish.fountain"&gt;BEFORE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://fountain.io/_downloads/Big%20Fish.pdf" title="Big Fish.pdf"&gt;AFTER&lt;/a&gt; example to help you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="whats-new-final-draft-support--multicam-support"&gt;What’s New: Final Draft Support &amp;amp; Multicam Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Fountain Loader can now not only preview screenplays but also convert fountain files into &lt;a href="https://www.finaldraft.com/" title="Official Final Draft - #1-Selling Screenwriting Software - Final Draft"&gt;Final Draft&lt;/a&gt; FDX files, complete with title pages. What’s more, it has some features that even Highland and Slugline lack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re writing a television script rather than a feature film script, Fountain Loader has built-in tools to make that easier. By labeling the top of your script with the “Format: Multicam” tag, Fountain Loader will automatically produce a Final Draft file with classic sitcom formatting. It will also convert Act Breaks into their proper Final Draft elements rather than just converting them into centered action text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Final Draft export feature also supports script notes and some really complicated overlapping text styles.&lt;sup id="fnref:brag"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:brag" class="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="google-docs-is-now-screenwriting-software"&gt;Google Docs is Now Screenwriting Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made this update because my writing partner and I were writing a multicam script, and everytime I wanted to check the page count, I had to copy and paste the script into Highland, output a Final Draft file, then open up Final Draft, import a multicam template, and then fix all the act breaks. Now that’s a one-click process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a huge improvement for us. Writing a screenplay collaboratively in Google Docs is now much, much easier. When we were staff writers on NBC’s About a Boy, we wrote our episode in Google Docs using fountain and Fountain Loader. Everything we write from now on will live in Google Docs and then end up in Final Draft only when we’re ready to distribute our scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="links"&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://fountainloader.com"&gt;http://fountainloader.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For more information about how Fountain Loader works, check out &lt;a href="http://simonganz.com/2014/06/fountain-loader-for-google-drive/"&gt;my original post announcing the project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you want to learn how to write in fountain, check out the &lt;a href="http://fountain.io/" title="Fountain - A markup language for screenwriting."&gt;fountain syntax page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class="footnotes"&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id="fn:brag"&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Fountain Loader does a good job with tricky, edge case Fountain formatting. &lt;strong&gt;EXAMPLE:&lt;/strong&gt; “_David is **stunned**. How could *she* do this ***to*** him?_” &lt;a href="#fnref:brag" class="reversefootnote"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>DeHulkifier Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2015/05/dehulkifier-update/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2015/05/dehulkifier-update/</id>
    <published>2015-05-02T22:06:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-02T22:06:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’ve released a small update to my &lt;a href="http://simonganz.com/2013/04/the-dehulkifier/"&gt;DeHulkifier bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt;. Film Crit Hulk moved to a &lt;a href="http://birthmoviesdeath.com"&gt;new website&lt;/a&gt;, so the bookmarklet needed to be tweaked to keep working.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Adding Search Links to Ranndy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2015/03/ranndy-random-name-generator-adding-search-links/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2015/03/ranndy-random-name-generator-adding-search-links/</id>
    <published>2015-03-12T18:09:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2015-03-12T18:09:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ranndy/search-links-0c34b61d.jpg" title="Ranndy Search Links Feature" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve released a small update to &lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;Ranndy.com&lt;/a&gt;, my random name generator site. Now every first and last name generated by the site contains a link to a Google search about that name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if I generate the surname “Swisher” and want to know more about it, I can click on the name and quickly learn that the name is Austrian and originally meant “person who lives near a hill, stream, or church.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when creating characters, I like to find last names that have hidden meanings and reflect the character’s personality.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ranndy Random Name Generator Updated</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/11/ranndy-random-name-generator-updated/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2014/11/ranndy-random-name-generator-updated/</id>
    <published>2014-11-29T11:35:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-11-29T11:35:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’ve released a new version of &lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;Ranndy.com&lt;/a&gt;, my random name generator for use in fiction writing and baby naming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-starts-with-feature"&gt;New Starts With Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy can now show you names that start with certain letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you enter “Jo” in the Starts With field, Ranndy will only show you names that start with “Jo” like John, Jordan, Jose, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ranndy/starts-with-7084fd8b.png" title="Ranndy Starts With Feature" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-exclusion-feature"&gt;New Exclusion Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy can also do the opposite of Starts With, showing you names that DON’T start with certain letters. Just use the * character in the Starts With field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you enter “D*, S*, P*” in the Starts With field, Ranndy won’t show you any names that start with D, S, or P. This is useful when you’re writing a screenplay and don’t want too many characters whose names sound or look similar on the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ranndy/exclusion-f38b31fd.png" title="Ranndy Exclusion Feature" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-force-name-feature"&gt;New Force Name Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy now lets you force a first or last name. If you already know a first or last name that you love, you can force that name with the ^ character in the Starts With field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you enter “Smith^” in the Last Name Starts With field, then Ranndy will show you random first names but every last name will be “Smith”. This is useful for baby naming and also creating family members for characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ranndy/force-name-f2e536d4.png" title="Ranndy Force Name Feature" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2 id="popularity-tweaks"&gt;Popularity Tweaks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also made some tweaks to how Ranndy ranks first names by popularity. The default setting of “High” popularity is now much broader, which should give a better variety of names without including too many weird names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="project-page"&gt;Project Page&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Ranndy, you can visit &lt;a href="http://simonganz.com/2014/06/ranndy-random-name-generator/" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;my first blog post about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
