<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>SimonGanz.com</title>
  <id>http://simonganz.com/</id>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/"/>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-08-18T01:54:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Simon Ganz</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Get a Free Gigabyte from Dropbox for Using Mailbox on iOS [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lifehacker.com/mailbox-users-can-get-a-free-gigabyte-of-dropbox-space-1159534393"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/08/get-a-free-gigabyte-from-dropbox-for-using-mailbox/</id>
    <published>2013-08-18T01:54:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-18T01:54:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Free space on &lt;a href="http://db.tt/DcIkRM3k"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; is worth its weight in gold. You get to keep it forever, and every additional megabyte postpones the day when you'll have to switch to their &lt;a href="http://www.dropbox.com/pricing"&gt;$100-a-year paid plan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, this week Dropbox is giving away free space if you try their iOS Gmail client, &lt;a href="http://www.mailboxapp.com/"&gt;Mailbox&lt;/a&gt; (also free). If you have an iOS device, &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mailbox/id576502633?mt=8"&gt;download the app&lt;/a&gt;, go to settings, and link it to your Dropbox account. You get the free gig of space immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#x27;/2013/08/get-a-free-gigabyte-from-dropbox-for-using-mailbox/&amp;#x27;&amp;gt;Permalink&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Using Ambient Noise to Drown Out Distraction</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/using-ambient-noise-to-drown-out-distraction/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/08/using-ambient-noise-to-drown-out-distraction/</id>
    <published>2013-08-10T04:14:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-10T04:14:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I struggle to work in silence. My mind gets crowded with ideas. But I also struggle to work with music. My mind begins to follow the lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ambient noise is a way to drown out your thoughts without distracting your focus. Here are three tools I recommend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="simplynoise"&gt;SimplyNoise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://simplynoise.com/" title="SimplyNoise -- The Best Free White Noise Generator on the Internet."&gt;SimplyNoise&lt;/a&gt; is a site that plays &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colors_of_noise" title="Wikipedia: Colors of noise"&gt;white, pink, and brown noise&lt;/a&gt;. There are many sites and many apps that do this, but in my opinion, SimplyNoise has the "cleanest" noise. I find other digital noise generators to be harsh or grating. Other generators also tend to loop in distracting ways. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don't like using an iPhone app or a web browser to play the noise, you can &lt;a href="http://simplynoise.com/downloads.html" title="SimplyNoise downloads"&gt;pay a dollar to download a 60-minute MP3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creates an intense sense of focus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Difficult to use alongside music. The noise is quickly overwhelmed by the lyrics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eventually drives you insane, like being locked in a hyperbaric chamber.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="get-work-done-music"&gt;Get Work Done Music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.getworkdonemusic.com/" title="Get Work Done Music"&gt;Get Work Done Music&lt;/a&gt; streams fast-paced music from &lt;a href="http://soundcloud.com/" title="SoundCloud - Share Your Sounds"&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;. The songs tend to be electronica/trance music, usually with pulsing rhythms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Variety.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You might actually discover artists that you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Depends on accurate SoundCloud tagging. Sometimes you get crazy demon-screaming garbage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="coffitivity"&gt;Coffitivity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://coffitivity.com/" title="Coffitivity - Increase Your Creativity!"&gt;Coffitivity&lt;/a&gt; is a site that plays coffee shop noises on a loop. This feels like a dumb idea. But when combined with music, it provides a pleasing mix of noise that is just enough to balance out your music's lyrics while still drowning out stray thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don't like using a web browser to play sound, you can just &lt;a href="http://coffitivity.com/other/cleanupcut.mp3" title="Coffitivity MP3 File"&gt;download the MP3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can play your own music.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don't feel like a total psychopath.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;None: This is what I use most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ The Hitlers of Pickaway, Ohio [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2013/07/life-in-ohio-a-continuing-series.html"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/08/the-hitlers-of-pickaway-ohio/</id>
    <published>2013-08-04T05:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-04T05:03:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dr. Gay Hitler, son of George Washington Hitler, was a local dentist, serving our community from 1922 through 1946 from his office on West Main Street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2013/07/life-in-ohio-a-continuing-series.html" title="Life in Ohio: A Continuing Series"&gt;Jonathan Chait&lt;/a&gt; highlights &lt;a href="http://www.circlevilletoday.com/news/hitlers-were-county-pioneers/article_2a6487b2-a34a-55f4-83f4-dfcf116d15d5.html" title="Hitlers were county pioneers"&gt;a great local newspaper story&lt;/a&gt; about the pioneering Hitler family of Pickaway, Ohio. A significant portion of the town is named after these honest, All-American, salt-of-the-earth Hitlers, and the townsfolk are tired of everyone thinking they're fans of the &lt;em&gt;slightly&lt;/em&gt; more famous Adolf Hitler.&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#x27;/2013/08/the-hitlers-of-pickaway-ohio/&amp;#x27;&amp;gt;Permalink&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Paul Offit and the Vitamin Myth [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2013/07/the-vitamin-myth-why-we-think-we-need-supplements/277947/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/07/dr-paul-offit-and-the-vitamin-myth/</id>
    <published>2013-07-31T02:14:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-31T02:14:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Seven previous studies had already shown that vitamins increased the risk of cancer and heart disease and shortened lives. Still, in 2012, more than half of all Americans took some form of vitamin supplements. What few people realize, however, is that their fascination with vitamins can be traced back to one man. A man who was so spectacularly right that he won two Nobel Prizes and so spectacularly wrong that he was arguably the world's greatest quack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ouch&lt;/em&gt;. The Atlantic has &lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2013/07/the-vitamin-myth-why-we-think-we-need-supplements/277947/" title="The Vitamin Myth: Why We Think We Need Supplements"&gt;a brutal book excerpt&lt;/a&gt; from Dr. Paul Offit tearing into the vitamin supplement industry. This is the same Dr. Offit who attacked the fake link between vaccines and autism in &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/023114637X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=023114637X&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=simongcom-20" title="Autism's False Prophets: Bad Science, Risky Medicine, and the Search for a Cure"&gt;an earlier book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've always treated vitamins like a reassuring and benign superstition. "I don't feel well, I guess I'll take some vitamins!" "I could use a pick-me-up, I'll drink some Emergen-C!" "My penis isn't long enough, I'll inject some Ostrich estrus!" (Okay not the last one.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Offit's article really shocked me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="rebuttals"&gt;Rebuttals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has of course been pushback. Dr. Paul Jaminet, an astrophysicist who writes diet books, has &lt;a href="http://perfecthealthdiet.com/2013/07/the-case-of-the-killer-vitamins-revisited/" title="The Case of the Killer Vitamins Revisited"&gt;a measured response&lt;/a&gt;. He takes issue with the specific studies cited by Offit, in particular an Iowa study which suggested that vitamins increase mortality (ie make you more likely to die) did not adjust for age. It compared older people who were taking supplements with younger people who were not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most compelling criticism is that the book excerpt blurs the line between taking a simple multivitamin and overdosing on Vitamin C because you think it'll help you shoot lasers from your eyes. In &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2013/jul/26/vitamins-health-paul-offit-qanda" title="Vitamins: Should You Stop Taking THem"&gt;an online interview with The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, Offit explains the distinction in less sensationlist terms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Other people think: “Because I'm not sure I'm getting all my vitamins, let me just take take a multivitamin every day” – which is OK. Multivitamins contain at or about the recommended dose of vitamins for that day. But then there are some people who believe that more is better – that by taking large quantities of daily vitamins they will do even better, live even longer and decrease the risk of cancer or heart disease. But in fact, many studies have shown that the exact opposite is true – that if you choose to take these large quantities of excess vitamins, then you increase risk of cancer and heart disease and shorten your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line: There just isn't much compelling evidence about vitamins despite decades of study. They make sense on an intellectual level, but the benefits are not clearly visible in repeatable studies. A well-formulated multivitamin is probably benign and not doing you any harm or good either way.&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#x27;/2013/07/dr-paul-offit-and-the-vitamin-myth/&amp;#x27;&amp;gt;Permalink&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Pacific Rim and the Flat American Accent [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://thedissolve.com/news/25-please-hollywood-no-more-bad-fake-american-accents/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/07/pacific-rim-and-the-flat-american-accent/</id>
    <published>2013-07-15T23:48:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-15T23:48:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Matt Singer at Dissolve has a sharp post on &lt;a href="http://thedissolve.com/news/25-please-hollywood-no-more-bad-fake-american-accents/" title="Please Hollywood, No More Fake American Accents"&gt;the rise of Europeans doing flat American accents in blockbuster films&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bale is from the United Kingdom as well, and variations of his flat, husky whisper—like a guy with a bad case of laryngitis and a mild speech impediment—have become the de facto “American” voice for a lot of foreign born Hollywood action heroes. Scottish Gerard Butler used it earlier this year as a Secret Service agent in Olympus Has Fallen; Australian Sam Worthington deployed it with varying degrees of success in Avatar and Terminator Salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What annoys me most about this particular fake accent is that it robs characters' voices of depth and subtlety. &lt;em&gt;Pacific Rim&lt;/em&gt; is a tremendously fun and goofy film, but its lead character has the vocal range of a robot. Jokes and important moments feel off because the actor is stuck talking like a stoic, Clint Eastwood cowboy rather than like a real person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not opposed to Brits and Europeans doing American accents, but the Bale voice is simply too flat and dreary to work for most films.&lt;/p&gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#x27;/2013/07/pacific-rim-and-the-flat-american-accent/&amp;#x27;&amp;gt;Permalink&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ The 1964 Civil Rights Act and Rand Paul Libertarians [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/moneybox/2013/06/21/civil_rights_act_good_rand_paul_bad.html"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/07/1964-civil-rights-act-and-rand-paul-libertarians/</id>
    <published>2013-07-11T19:32:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-11T19:32:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The "respectable" thing to say about people like Paul or the late Barry Goldwater, I suppose, is simply that they are ideologues rather than people driven by some kind of racial animosity. But I think it's selling free market ideology short to suggest that government regulations meant to undue the outcome of a century long campaign of terrorist violence is just a straightforward consequence of a general support for free enterprise. You need to combine that ideology with a sincere indifference to black people's welfare to reach that conclusion, just as you need to combine Paul's ideology with genuine indifference to the history of race in America to reach Paul's conclusion about democracy's relationship to Jim Crow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Yglesias wrote &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/moneybox/2013/06/21/civil_rights_act_good_rand_paul_bad.html" title="The Civil Rights Act is Good"&gt;an excellent post&lt;/a&gt; last month about Rand Paul's foot-in-mouth statements opposing the 1964 Civil Rights Act. Jonathan Chait covered similar ground in &lt;a href="http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2012/01/how-ron-pauls-libertarianism-supports-racism.html" title="How Ron Paul's Libertarianism Supports Racism"&gt;a 2012 post about Rand's father, Ron Paul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron and Rand Paul are beloved libertarian figures on the internet because they follow libertarian philosophy to some of its more progressive conclusions, like reducing defense spending and decriminalizing drugs. In this and a few other areas, they give loud and passionate voice to sensible solutions drowned out by mainstream politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it's worth remembering that libertarianism in this country has often been driven by racism rather than ideology. This is not to say that all libertarians are racists or that libertarianism is an inherently racist philosophy, but when I read about &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/fact-checker/post/ron-paul-and-the-racist-newsletters-fact-checker-biography/2011/12/21/gIQAKNiwBP_blog.html" title="Fact Check: Ron Paul's Racist Newsletters"&gt;Ron Paul's racist 1990s newsletters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://crooksandliars.com/blue-texan/rand-pauls-opposition-civil-rights-act" title="Rand Paul's Racist Aide"&gt;Rand Paul's aide's racist, secessionist writings&lt;/a&gt;, it becomes harder and harder to square the internet's hero worship of these men with the actual motivations guiding them.&lt;/p&gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#x27;/2013/07/1964-civil-rights-act-and-rand-paul-libertarians/&amp;#x27;&amp;gt;Permalink&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
