<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>SimonGanz.com</title>
  <id>http://simonganz.com/</id>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/"/>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-08-25T21:18:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Simon Ganz</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>About a Babymoon</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2015/08/about-a-babymoon/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2015/08/about-a-babymoon/</id>
    <published>2015-08-25T21:18:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-25T21:18:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;img src="/images/about-a-boy-de83aa38.jpg" title="About a Boy" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though NBC cancelled About a Boy earlier this year, thankfully the episode my partner and I wrote was still made and produced. Episode 217, About a Babymoon, is now available online at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/About-a-Babymoon/dp/B011CGNKQQ/ref=as_sl_pc_qf_sp_asin_til?tag=simongcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w00&amp;amp;linkId=AX2W3CAHYG63LZZW&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B011CGNKQQ"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/tv-season/about-a-babymoon/id916041060?i=1020546458"&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fountain Loader 2.0</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2015/06/fountain-loader-2-0/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2015/06/fountain-loader-2-0/</id>
    <published>2015-06-29T07:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-29T07:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;p&gt;I’m releasing a major new update to my screenwriting app, &lt;a title="Fountain Loader for Google Docs" href="http://fountainloader.com"&gt;Fountain Loader&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="video-container"&gt;
    &lt;video autoplay loop controls poster="http://fountainloader.com/videos/fountain-loader-2.png"&gt;
    &lt;source id="webmsource" src="http://fountainloader.com/videos/fountain-loader-2.webm" type="video/webm"&gt;
    &lt;source id="mp4source" src="http://fountainloader.com/videos/fountain-loader-2.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;
    &lt;img src="http://fountainloader.com/videos/fountain-loader-2.gif"&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quickly recap, Fountain Loader is a web app that makes it easy to write screenplays in Google Docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It builds off the brilliant work of &lt;a title="John August" href="http://johnaugust.com/"&gt;John August&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Nima Yousefi" href="http://nimayousefi.com/"&gt;Nima Yousefi&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a title="Prolost" href="http://prolost.com/"&gt;Stu Maschwitz&lt;/a&gt; who created the &lt;a title="Fountain - A markup language for screenwriting." href="http://fountain.io/"&gt;fountain screenwriting format&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the hell is a screenwriting format? Well fountain is really just a basic set of formatting rules. If you write text that follows those rules, then that text can be easily converted into a finished screenplay using great programs like &lt;a title="Highland - Quote-Unquote Apps" href="http://quoteunquoteapps.com/highland/"&gt;Highland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Slugline. Simply Screenwriting." href="http://slugline.co/"&gt;Slugline&lt;/a&gt;, and now Fountain Loader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a &lt;a title="Big Fish.fountain" href="http://fountain.io/_downloads/Big%20Fish.fountain"&gt;BEFORE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Big Fish.pdf" href="http://fountain.io/_downloads/Big%20Fish.pdf"&gt;AFTER&lt;/a&gt; example to help you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="whats-new-final-draft-support--multicam-support"&gt;What’s New: Final Draft Support &amp;amp; Multicam Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Fountain Loader can now not only preview screenplays but also convert fountain files into &lt;a title="Official Final Draft - #1-Selling Screenwriting Software - Final Draft" href="https://www.finaldraft.com/"&gt;Final Draft&lt;/a&gt; FDX files, complete with title pages. What’s more, it has some features that even Highland and Slugline lack. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re writing a television script rather than a feature film script, Fountain Loader has built-in tools to make that easier. By labeling the top of your script with the “Format: Multicam” tag, Fountain Loader will automatically produce a Final Draft file with classic sitcom formatting. It will also convert Act Breaks into their proper Final Draft elements rather than just converting them into centered action text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Final Draft export feature also supports script notes and some really complicated overlapping text styles.&lt;sup id="fnref:brag"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:brag" class="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="google-docs-is-now-screenwriting-software"&gt;Google Docs is Now Screenwriting Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made this update because my writing partner and I were writing a multicam script, and everytime I wanted to check the page count, I had to copy and paste the script into Highland, output a Final Draft file, then open up Final Draft, import a multicam template, and then fix all the act breaks. Now that’s a one-click process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a huge improvement for us. Writing a screenplay collaboratively in Google Docs is now much, much easier. When we were staff writers on NBC’s About a Boy, we wrote our episode in Google Docs using fountain and Fountain Loader. Everything we write from now on will live in Google Docs and then end up in Final Draft only when we’re ready to distribute our scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="links"&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://fountainloader.com"&gt;http://fountainloader.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For more information about how Fountain Loader works, check out &lt;a href="http://simonganz.com/2014/06/fountain-loader-for-google-drive/"&gt;my original post announcing the project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you want to learn how to write in fountain, check out the &lt;a title="Fountain - A markup language for screenwriting." href="http://fountain.io/"&gt;fountain syntax page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class="footnotes"&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id="fn:brag"&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Fountain Loader does a good job with tricky, edge case Fountain formatting. &lt;strong&gt;EXAMPLE:&lt;/strong&gt; “_David is **stunned**. How could *she* do this ***to*** him?_” &lt;a href="#fnref:brag" class="reversefootnote"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>DeHulkifier Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2015/05/dehulkifier-update/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2015/05/dehulkifier-update/</id>
    <published>2015-05-02T22:06:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-02T22:06:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;p&gt;I’ve released a small update to my &lt;a href="http://simonganz.com/2013/04/the-dehulkifier/"&gt;DeHulkifier bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt;. Film Crit Hulk moved to a &lt;a href="http://birthmoviesdeath.com"&gt;new website&lt;/a&gt;, so the bookmarklet needed to be tweaked to keep working.&lt;/p&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Adding Search Links to Ranndy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2015/03/ranndy-random-name-generator-adding-search-links/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2015/03/ranndy-random-name-generator-adding-search-links/</id>
    <published>2015-03-12T18:09:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2015-03-12T18:09:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ranndy/search-links-0c34b61d.jpg" title="Ranndy Search Links Feature" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve released a small update to &lt;a title="Ranndy Random Name Generator" href="http://ranndy.com"&gt;Ranndy.com&lt;/a&gt;, my random name generator site. Now every first and last name generated by the site contains a link to a Google search about that name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if I generate the surname “Swisher” and want to know more about it, I can click on the name and quickly learn that the name is Austrian and originally meant “person who lives near a hill, stream, or church.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when creating characters, I like to find last names that have hidden meanings and reflect the character’s personality.&lt;/p&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ranndy Random Name Generator Updated</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/11/ranndy-random-name-generator-updated/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2014/11/ranndy-random-name-generator-updated/</id>
    <published>2014-11-29T11:35:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-11-29T11:35:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;p&gt;I’ve released a new version of &lt;a title="Ranndy Random Name Generator" href="http://ranndy.com"&gt;Ranndy.com&lt;/a&gt;, my random name generator for use in fiction writing and baby naming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-starts-with-feature"&gt;New Starts With Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy can now show you names that start with certain letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you enter “Jo” in the Starts With field, Ranndy will only show you names that start with “Jo” like John, Jordan, Jose, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ranndy/starts-with-7084fd8b.png" title="Ranndy Starts With Feature" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-exclusion-feature"&gt;New Exclusion Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy can also do the opposite of Starts With, showing you names that DON’T start with certain letters. Just use the * character in the Starts With field. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you enter “D*, S*, P*” in the Starts With field, Ranndy won’t show you any names that start with D, S, or P. This is useful when you’re writing a screenplay and don’t want too many characters whose names sound or look similar on the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ranndy/exclusion-f38b31fd.png" title="Ranndy Exclusion Feature" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-force-name-feature"&gt;New Force Name Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranndy now lets you force a first or last name. If you already know a first or last name that you love, you can force that name with the ^ character in the Starts With field. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you enter “Smith^” in the Last Name Starts With field, then Ranndy will show you random first names but every last name will be “Smith”. This is useful for baby naming and also creating family members for characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;a href="http://ranndy.com" title="Ranndy Random Name Generator"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ranndy/force-name-f2e536d4.png" title="Ranndy Force Name Feature" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2 id="popularity-tweaks"&gt;Popularity Tweaks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also made some tweaks to how Ranndy ranks first names by popularity. The default setting of “High” popularity is now much broader, which should give a better variety of names without including too many weird names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="project-page"&gt;Project Page&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Ranndy, you can visit &lt;a title="Ranndy Random Name Generator" href="http://simonganz.com/2014/06/ranndy-random-name-generator/"&gt;my first blog post about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Making a Digital Will for Your Online Accounts</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/09/making-a-digital-will-for-your-online-accounts/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2014/09/making-a-digital-will-for-your-online-accounts/</id>
    <published>2014-09-21T16:23:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2014-09-21T16:23:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content>
      <div>&lt;h2 id="the-problem-death"&gt;The Problem: Death&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/death-d17bddd2.jpg" title="Death" /&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align:right; margin-bottom: -20px;"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/pedrosz/5578743262/in/photolist-dqGruE-5SuHtq-6dbaBf-8DDXGt-bsKmci-9aRZK2-7U24t8-4CwBoY-4wskbr-9uYw1E-m9jryL-7Z5xz2-9cb36s-9cAs7C-9LDkcC-dqGrFL-dYN8NR-9i2q1m-nsNaSW-c2Z8S9-dqGhvn-ot7cxc-9jRzE5-ahoi86-2yKq35-eg9fuW-9kuX6N-9atqQ-8h7tpM-mUepW-cYWWj3-4JvWT4-57WvKT-bndFjR-cLh3pw-7cvtQ2-aVFXc-ePGGNz-9d51VP-dqGrxb-9dnysQ-5i9jvH-58jZXm-a2uYFY-ft1G9Z-6UfB3T-3Tu6bj-8dwz8q-4y9XXp-9G8Z8c/"&gt;© Pedro Szekely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m the designated nerd in my family, so I handle all of our online accounts. To keep them secure, I use randomly generated, unique passwords and two-factor authentication. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that means that my wife doesn’t know the online logins for our iTunes account, our bank and retirement accounts, our gas company, our cable company, our water and power company, and so on and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if I died or was suddenly incapacitated? How would she access our accounts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need a system that’s secure. I don’t want to weaken all my online accounts just for the off chance that I get hit by a bus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need a system that can outlive my hardware. What if my hypothetical death also destroyed my laptop, tablet, and phone?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need a system that can be easily understood by my tech illiterate survivors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-solution"&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="ingredient-list"&gt;Ingredient List&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="1Password - AgileBits" href="https://agilebits.com/onepassword"&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="Dropbox" href="https://www.dropbox.com/"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Printed or handwritten letter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secure physical location (safe, deposit box, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="step-one-put-all-your-passwords-in-1password"&gt;Step One: Put all your passwords in 1Password&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="1Password - AgileBits" href="https://agilebits.com/onepassword"&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; is a password management app available for Mac, Windows, and iOS. It saves your passwords in a secure vault with a master password. Instead of having to remember hundreds of weak passwords, you only have to remember one strong password. The app can generate random, unique passwords for all your online accounts, so if a service gets hacked, your other accounts are safe because each has a unique and unguessable password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="step-two-put-your-1password-vault-in-dropbox"&gt;Step Two: Put your 1Password vault in Dropbox&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1Password can &lt;a title="How To: Configure Dropbox Syncing" href="https://help.agilebits.com/1Password3/configure_dropbox_on_mac.html"&gt;store your secure password vault in your Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; account. That means that by leaving detailed instructions and a few key passwords, all of your online account information can be accessed from one simple file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="step-three-write-a-letter-explaining-how-to-access-your-dropbox-account-and-1password-vault"&gt;Step Three: Write a letter explaining how to access your Dropbox account and 1Password vault&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The letter should be stored in a secure location like a safe or safety deposit box in a sealed envelope with the date written on it. And you should tell people important to you about the letter and where to find it. If you have a legal will for your estate, you should mention the letter in that will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing the letter is the hardest step. It should include the following information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your email account username and password. If your family needs to reset any of your passwords, they’ll need access to your email.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Dropbox username and password.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your 1Password Master Password.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your passcode for your cellphone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Detailed instructions for how to access the 1Password master vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id="example-text"&gt;Example Text&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some example text from my own letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accessing a two-factor authentication protected gmail account:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My Gmail account is protected with two-factor authentication. This means you need both my password and the Google Authenticator app on my iPhone in order to access it. If you can’t access my phone, you can use a special one-time only backup code to get into my Gmail account without using the authenticator. Once you log in with a backup code, you should turn off two-factor authentication so that you don’t get locked out of the account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accessing Dropbox and 1Password:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My writing as well as an encrypted archive containing all of my online passwords can be found in my Dropbox account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Inside my Dropbox is a file called 1Password.agilekeychain. 
This is an encrypted archive that contains all of my passwords, including those for important accounts like my bank account. It can be opened using a program called 1Password which is available at https://agilebits.com/onepassword. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id="bonus-list-your-online-assets"&gt;Bonus: List Your Online Assets&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passing on all of your online accounts to your survivors isn’t useful if they don’t know what’s worth saving. At the end of the letter, write down a list of every online asset that’s important or valuable to you. For instance, web domains, online photo storage accounts, and anything you’ve written online and want preserved.&lt;/p&gt;

</div>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
