<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>SimonGanz.com</title>
  <id>http://simonganz.com/</id>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/"/>
  <link href="http://simonganz.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-07-15T23:48:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Simon Ganz</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>→ Pacific Rim and the Flat, American Accent [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://thedissolve.com/news/25-please-hollywood-no-more-bad-fake-american-accents/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/07/pacific-rim-and-the-flat-american-accent/</id>
    <published>2013-07-15T23:48:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-15T23:48:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Matt Singer at Dissolve has a sharp post on &lt;a href="http://thedissolve.com/news/25-please-hollywood-no-more-bad-fake-american-accents/" title="Please Hollywood, No More Fake American Accents"&gt;the rise of Europeans doing flat American accents in blockbuster films&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bale is from the United Kingdom as well, and variations of his flat, husky whisper—like a guy with a bad case of laryngitis and a mild speech impediment—have become the de facto “American” voice for a lot of foreign born Hollywood action heroes. Scottish Gerard Butler used it earlier this year as a Secret Service agent in Olympus Has Fallen; Australian Sam Worthington deployed it with varying degrees of success in Avatar and Terminator Salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What annoys me most about this particular fake accent is that it robs characters' voices of depth and subtlety. &lt;em&gt;Pacific Rim&lt;/em&gt; is a tremendously fun and goofy film, but its lead character has the vocal range of a robot. Jokes and important moments feel off because the actor is stuck talking like a stoic, Clint Eastwood cowboy rather than like a real person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not opposed to Brits and Europeans doing American accents, but the Bale voice is simply too flat and dreary to work for most films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/07/pacific-rim-and-the-flat-american-accent/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>→ The 1964 Civil Rights Act and Rand Paul Libertarians [link]</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/moneybox/2013/06/21/civil_rights_act_good_rand_paul_bad.html"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/07/1964-civil-rights-act-and-rand-paul-libertarians/</id>
    <published>2013-07-11T19:32:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-11T19:32:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The "respectable" thing to say about people like Paul or the late Barry Goldwater, I suppose, is simply that they are ideologues rather than people driven by some kind of racial animosity. But I think it's selling free market ideology short to suggest that government regulations meant to undue the outcome of a century long campaign of terrorist violence is just a straightforward consequence of a general support for free enterprise. You need to combine that ideology with a sincere indifference to black people's welfare to reach that conclusion, just as you need to combine Paul's ideology with genuine indifference to the history of race in America to reach Paul's conclusion about democracy's relationship to Jim Crow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Yglesias wrote &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/moneybox/2013/06/21/civil_rights_act_good_rand_paul_bad.html" title="The Civil Rights Act is Good"&gt;an excellent post&lt;/a&gt; last month about Rand Paul's foot-in-mouth statements opposing the 1964 Civil Rights Act. Jonathan Chait covered similar ground in &lt;a href="http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2012/01/how-ron-pauls-libertarianism-supports-racism.html" title="How Ron Paul's Libertarianism Supports Racism"&gt;a 2012 post about Rand's father, Ron Paul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron and Rand Paul are beloved libertarian figures on the internet because they follow libertarian philosophy to some of its more progressive conclusions, like reducing defense spending and decriminalizing drugs. In this and a few other areas, they give loud and passionate voice to sensible solutions drowned out by mainstream politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it's worth remembering that libertarianism in this country has often been driven by racism rather than ideology. This is not to say that all libertarians are racists or that libertarianism is an inherently racist philosophy, but when I read about &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/fact-checker/post/ron-paul-and-the-racist-newsletters-fact-checker-biography/2011/12/21/gIQAKNiwBP_blog.html" title="Fact Check: Ron Paul's Racist Newsletters"&gt;Ron Paul's racist 1990s newsletters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://crooksandliars.com/blue-texan/rand-pauls-opposition-civil-rights-act" title="Rand Paul's Racist Aide"&gt;Rand Paul's aide's racist, secessionist writings&lt;/a&gt;, it becomes harder and harder to square the internet's hero worship of these men with the actual motivations guiding them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='/2013/07/1964-civil-rights-act-and-rand-paul-libertarians/'&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Google Reader Alternatives</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/07/google-reader-alternatives/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/07/google-reader-alternatives/</id>
    <published>2013-07-08T19:21:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-08T19:21:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Google recently &lt;a href="http://simonganz.com/2013/06/why-google-killed-reader/" title="Why Google Killed Reader"&gt;shut down Google Reader&lt;/a&gt;, their RSS syncing service. Here's a quick look at three replacements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="feedly"&gt;Feedly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.feedly.com/" title="feedly: your news. delivered."&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; is the most popular Google Reader replacement because it's free and fast. But a few key problems prevented me from choosing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedly has &lt;strong&gt;a closed API&lt;/strong&gt;. I have custom scripts and hacks I use for my RSS, and they require an open API. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedly also has &lt;strong&gt;no clear business model&lt;/strong&gt;. Free is great, but after Google Reader's epic flameout, it's hard to trust a service that doesn't ask for money. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, &lt;strong&gt;Feedly's website and apps are over-designed and confusing&lt;/strong&gt;. Feedly seems desperate to become &lt;a href="http://flipboard.com/" title="Flipboard"&gt;Flipboard&lt;/a&gt;, so their default layout is a magazine-style look at your RSS. You can switch to a "titles only" view that looks more like Google Reader, but you still have to deal with bizarre gestures and interactions in their iOS apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these criticisms, Feedly is a strong service. If they open up their API, I'll consider switching to them and just using third-party apps to access the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="feed-wrangler"&gt;Feed Wrangler&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedwrangler.net/" title="Feed Wrangler"&gt;Feed Wrangler&lt;/a&gt; is a small, paid RSS syncing service created by iOS developer &lt;a href="http://david-smith.org/" title="David Smith"&gt;David Smith&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several writers and programmers in the tech community sing the praises of this service, but I couldn't get over two things: &lt;strong&gt;No free trial&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;an ugly, ugly, ugly website&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="feedbin"&gt;Feedbin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://feedbin.me/" title="Feedbin"&gt;Feedbin&lt;/a&gt; is a small, paid RSS syncing service created by Ruby on Rails developer &lt;a href="http://benubois.com/about.html" title="Ben Ubois"&gt;Ben Ubois&lt;/a&gt;. It's &lt;strong&gt;$30-a-year&lt;/strong&gt;, has an &lt;strong&gt;attractive website&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;an open API&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="winner-feedbin"&gt;Winner: Feedbin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedbin is my new RSS reader. For now. The RSS market is changing fast, and I expect to revisit my choice a year from now when it's time to renew my subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Amazon Fresh Review</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/07/amazon-fresh-review-first-impressions/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/07/amazon-fresh-review-first-impressions/</id>
    <published>2013-07-05T18:40:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-05T18:40:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src="/images/amazonFresh-d264c4ed.jpg" title="Amazon Fresh" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon Fresh is Amazon's new grocery delivery business. They've just expanded to Los Angeles and offered &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/prime" title="Amazon Prime"&gt;Prime&lt;/a&gt; customers a 90-day free trial (the regular price is $300-a-year). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm interested in the service because I'm lazy and find supermarkets overwhelming. My wife is interested because she likes planning meals and tracking calories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are our first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-good"&gt;The Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon Fresh promises &lt;strong&gt;same day and next day delivery&lt;/strong&gt;, which is amazing. The minimum order is $35, which is low enough that you can replace a big weekly grocery store visit with two small orders during the week. You can place your order at night after work, then wake up in the morning to find your food on the doorstep in neatly packed bags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fresh also offers &lt;strong&gt;nutritional information&lt;/strong&gt; for many items on their site as well as &lt;strong&gt;seasonal recipes&lt;/strong&gt;. You can even order &lt;strong&gt;high end items from local specialty shops&lt;/strong&gt;, like fresh fish from Santa Monica Seafood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;customer service is great&lt;/strong&gt;, responding almost instantly to any inquiry or problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-bad"&gt;The Bad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Amazon Fresh feels &lt;strong&gt;like shopping at a Whole Foods connected to a Costco&lt;/strong&gt;. You want some tuna? Great! You can have this ultra high quality organic brand for three times the price! Oh, you want your regular cheap brand? Okay, here's a 75-pack of Bumblebee tuna cans for $90!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The economics of home delivery cause the service to offer &lt;strong&gt;either high-end brands at high prices or the regular brand in massive quantities&lt;/strong&gt;, with little in-between. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://fresh.amazon.com" title="Amazon Fresh"&gt;Fresh.Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt; is a bad, sloooooow website&lt;/strong&gt;. It's shockingly bad. Amazon isn't just the world's biggest Internet retailer, they also operate a massive cloud server and cloud hosting service. But just logging into this site takes 15 to 20 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to being slow, the website does a &lt;strong&gt;poor job of reliably communicating which items are available when&lt;/strong&gt;. Orders placed for the next morning will often arrive with &lt;strong&gt;items missing&lt;/strong&gt;. There is no notice inside the packaging itself, instead you receive an email which says "The following items were not delivered: " and then nothing is actually listed. If you're dedicated you can go to the website, log into your past orders, and see which items were mysteriously left out. The site has &lt;strong&gt;no mechanism for rolling over a missing item to a future order&lt;/strong&gt;. The items are just gone, leaving you to find them again in the search system, re-add them to your cart, and just hope that it works out next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="odds--ends"&gt;Odds &amp;amp; Ends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prices on Amazon Fresh are just okay. They're not as good as your local market's sale prices but not as bad as &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suggested_retail_price" title="Suggested retail price - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia"&gt;MSRP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fresh includes same day and next day delivery on over 500,000 Amazon Prime items. It's only a small subset of Amazon's usual offerings, but you can buy household items like a surge protector with nearly instant shipping.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon failed to deliver half of one of our grocery orders. The customer service not only called me but refunded the entire order, including the more expensive items that they did successfully deliver.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fresh deliveries arrive in charming green tote bags. Oddly, the service doesn't do a good job combining similar items. So you might have two big coolers arrive, each packed with dry ice and each only carrying one tiny frozen item like a bag of peas or a pack of popsicles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, Fresh does not feel like the future of groceries. It feels like a side project. Perhaps a hobby receiving only Amazon's barest attention and focus. While using the service, I've already had to hop out to my regular market twice just to replace items missing from my orders. Combine that with the slow website, and Fresh just hasn't offered me the convenience necessary to justify the increased cost over my local market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I'm glad that Amazon Fresh has a 90-day trial. If my trial were ending today, I would not renew the service. But I have nearly two months of free grocery delivery left, and I think a lot of these problems are fixable. I'd love for this service to work out, and I'm going to continue to send feedback to Amazon's excellent customer service in the hopes that they're out there listening.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why Man of Steel's Action Sucked</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/07/man-of-steel-was-a-bad-action-movie/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/07/man-of-steel-was-a-bad-action-movie/</id>
    <published>2013-07-03T19:27:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-03T19:27:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src="/images/manOfSteel-080bcde9.jpg" title="Man of Steel" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not like Man of Steel. If you want to know why, I recommend two posts about the film: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rob Bricken's &lt;a href="http://io9.com/the-most-important-scenes-from-man-of-steel-as-i-remem-516405346" title="The Most Important Scenes from Man of Steel as I remember Them"&gt;hilarious Man of Steel recap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Film Crit Hulk's &lt;a href="http://badassdigest.com/2013/07/03/film-crit-hulk-man-of-steel/" title="The Importance of Dramatizing Character"&gt;lengthy, rambling, and totally spot on review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id="fnref:dehulkifier"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:dehulkifier" class="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do want to touch on one idea that I haven't seen explored much in reviews of the film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="good-action-requires-consequences-and-character"&gt;Good Action Requires Consequences and Character&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common defense of Man of Steel is that it has "good action." The movie has &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; special effects sequences, featuring superpowered fist fights, flying dragon-butterfly monsters, laser eye-battles, etc… In short, superhero battles on a level never before attempted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And all of that action is boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man of Steel lacks original or inventive ideas for its superhero fight scenes. Characters line up and punch and hit each other through building after building. "Pow! Superman crashes into a bank vault!" "Blammo! Zod plows through a gas station!" The spectacle entertains for about fifteen minutes, but the movie never finds a second gear. Superman and Zod are invulnerable. There are no consequences to each punch or each moment in any particular fight scene. Perhaps sensing this problem, the movie tries to blow up bigger and bigger buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The action scenes also lack character. We rarely understand the personal stakes in each fight. Superman has an elaborate brawl with three Kryptonians that destroys his home town of Smallville and at the end… &lt;em&gt;Nothing&lt;/em&gt;. The villains just fly away because they got tired of fighting. That's because there is nothing at stake in the scene for them. The characters simply fight to fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What's so sad about this is that fun goofy action shouldn't require you to turn your brain off or ignore the story. Just look at the batpod sequence in &lt;em&gt;The Dark Knight&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="video-container"&gt;
  &lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/FPaTv98wUsE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Dark Knight&lt;/em&gt; batpod sequence is much, much smaller than even the opening action scenes in Man of Steel, but it feels grounded and visceral. Harvey Dent, a character we've spent significant time with, is in mortal peril after bravely standing up to the Joker by claiming that he is Batman. If the Joker kills Harvey, the city will be thrown into further panic and chaos. Also in the audience's mind: Harvey and Batman are competing for the same woman, Rachel, so Batman saving Harvey will have significant personal consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But forget all that character shit. Isn't this sequence fucking fun!? Batman reveals his batmobile can turn into a crazy sideways motorcycle, races across Gotham, drives through a mall, plays chicken with a semi-truck, swoops under the truck, flips the truck AT-AT style, then drives up a wall to turn around? HOLY SHIT THAT WAS COOL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I defy anyone to find one sequence in Man of Steel even half as unexpected and entertaining as this &lt;em&gt;Dark Knight&lt;/em&gt; sequence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class="footnotes"&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id="fn:dehulkifier"&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You can read Hulk's article using my &lt;a href="http://simonganz.com/2013/04/the-dehulkifier/" title="The Dehulkifier"&gt;DeHulkifier bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href="#fnref:dehulkifier" class="reversefootnote"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mac OS X Stuck Registering Updated Components</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/07/mac-os-x-stuck-registering-updated-components/"/>
    <id>http://simonganz.com/2013/07/mac-os-x-stuck-registering-updated-components/</id>
    <published>2013-07-01T22:43:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-01T22:43:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Ganz</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently tried to run software update on my dad's aging Macbook Pro (Snow Leopard, Unibody). Unfortunately, the process stalled during "Registering Updated Components", leaving the computer stuck in the install for 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's how I fixed it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you're sure the install is stuck, hold down the power button to forcibly shut down the computer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restart the computer and open Finder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type ⇧⌘G to bring up the "Go To Folder…" dialogue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type /Library/Updates and hit enter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delete everything in the Updates folder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run Software Update again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, the security update dad's computer was trying to install was somehow corrupted. Redownloading it generated a fresh copy. I hope this is helpful to someone out there with the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
